<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>&lt;img src=&#39;/images/logo.png&#39; style=&#39;width: 2.2em; height: 2.2em; border-radius: 30%;&#39;&gt; &lt;b&gt;Canvass And Analyze&lt;/b&gt;</title>
<link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/</link>
<atom:link href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>My thought process on confluence of Psychology, Analytics and Management.</description>
<generator>quarto-1.7.30</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 04:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>LOVE &amp; TRUST - Season -1 | Episode - 8</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode8/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>Continued from previous blogs -&nbsp; <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode1" class="uri">Ep-1</a> -&nbsp; <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode2" class="uri">Ep-2</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode3/" class="uri">Ep-3</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode4/" class="uri">Ep-4</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode5/" class="uri">Ep-5</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode6/" class="uri">Ep-6</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode7/" class="uri">Ep-7</a></p>
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode8/image.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<hr>
<p>The rain kept pounding mercilessly as if the sky itself refused to forgive.</p>
<p>Raj sat with his head bowed, lost in thought. Guilt wrapped around his chest like wet cloth, heavy and cold. He was split and torn between Swati’s love and his actions on Sanjay’s .</p>
<p><strong>“Babe, what are you thinking?”</strong> Swati asked softly.</p>
<p>Raj looked up. Her eyes met his…. wide, open, shining with innocence and pure love. For a moment, he felt cherished. To be loved by someone like her, to have a heart that throbbed only for him… it was more than he thought he deserved.</p>
<p>But the glow from her kiss was gone. His face betrayed something she didn’t yet see.</p>
<p>“Babe… don’t look at me like that. I get so shy, you know it!” She giggled, playfully hiding her blush.</p>
<p>Raj blinked, grounding himself. “Nothing, babe. Just… still thinking about Sanjay. What I’ve done. But… I’m proud of you.”</p>
<p>He said it aloud. But inside, a quieter voice spoke back to him: <em>“Raj, you know who you are. Don’t you?”</em></p>
<p>Swati smiled brightly. “Babe, I’m so glad you’re proud of me. And just this once, forget about your so-called friend Sanjay, okay?”</p>
<p>Raj forced a nod, shrugging off the voice inside. “Yes, babe. I will.” Then he paused. “I have a request.”</p>
<p><strong>“Babe… what is it? You’re hesitating. It’s cute.”</strong></p>
<p>“It’s just… I never asked before, so I was unsure.” He looked at her. “Would you… come home with me tonight? Stay over?”</p>
<p>Swati’s face lit up, cheeks flushed with joy. “Babe… of course. I’ve always dreamt…. If you’re inviting me into your space, it’s like… like you’re asking me into your life. Like marriage. I’m in.”</p>
<p>Raj smiled. On the surface. Inside, he felt broken. Flawed. Something unspoken still pulsed in his ribs.</p>
<p>“Can you drive?” he asked quietly. “I’m… a little afraid to drive in this rain.” It wasn’t the rain. It was the weight inside him. The hangover of emotion he didn’t know how to carry.</p>
<p>Swati took the keys without hesitation.</p>
<p>They drove in silence. And when they reached, they stayed up and talked the entire night.</p>
<p>Swati was elated. Alive. Dreaming wide-eyed, heart-first.</p>
<p>Raj spoke gently. Smiled at the right moments. But inside, he was hollow.. like he had stepped outside himself and left his soul somewhere in the rain.</p>
<hr>
<p>Pooja’s anxiety deepened as the rain grew stronger. The words Meera had read from the Gita brought her no comfort.</p>
<p>“Ma’am… this isn’t helping me right now,” Pooja said bluntly, her voice brittle but honest.</p>
<p>Meera met her gaze… anxious and trembling.. and gently set the Gita aside.</p>
<p>She stood up and reached for her. Then, she wrapped her arms tightly around Pooja and whispered, “I’m with you. I’ve always told you.. I’m like your mother. Don’t worry, dear.”</p>
<p>Pooja clung to her, sobbing into Meera’s shoulder aned poured tears like the rain outside. Meera said nothing. Just held her. One hand tapping her back. The other resting on her shoulder. “It’s okay, dear. It’s okay…”</p>
<p>Five minutes passed in silence.</p>
<p>Then, slowly, Pooja pulled back. Her breath had steadied. Her tears had slowed. Outside, the rain had softened too. After the downpour … the air felt quieter.</p>
<p>Meera glanced at her gently. “It’s been almost thirty minutes since we had tea. You should try to rest now. I’ll stay here tonight … Is that alright with you?”</p>
<p>Pooja nodded. Something in her chest had unknotted. She hugged Meera again, this time like a child who had finally been understood. “Thank you, Ma’am… for staying.”</p>
<p>Then, without being told, she sat up straighter. Her posture looks still tired, but composed.</p>
<p>She picked up the Gita from the table and held it with quiet reverence. “Ma’am… you always tell me — when I lose my way, open the Gita and read whatever comes. Let me try that tonight. Let me see what God wants me to hear.”</p>
<p>She flipped through the pages. She took a breath… and read aloud:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>duḥkheṣhv-anudvigna-manāḥ sukheṣhu vigata-spṛihaḥ<br>
vīta-rāga-bhaya-krodhaḥ sthita-dhīr munir uchyate</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p>Pravallika screamed, “Sanjay… Sanjay… Sanjay… I love you… but…” Her voice cracked before the sentence could finish.</p>
<p>Just then, her phone buzzed. “Reminder: As per contract, your video must be uploaded tonight.”</p>
<p>She typed back instantly, frustrated. “No! I can’t do it.”</p>
<p>The reply came within seconds. “Either fulfill the contract or break it and in both cases, the penalty applies.”</p>
<p>She sighed, grinding her teeth. “Fine. What’s the penalty?”</p>
<p><strong>“₹1 crore.”</strong></p>
<p>“What?!”</p>
<p>“Yes, ma’am. It was detailed in the digital contract. The penalty scales with your follower count. You have over 100K followers, so you’re in the high-tier bracket.”</p>
<p>Pravallika’s anger boiled over…. not just at the company, but at herself. At Sanjay. At the fact that she now had to create a video.</p>
<p>She stared at the screen. Then typed with a mix of resignation and rage, “Fine. I’ll send an AI version in an hour.”</p>
<p>“Thanks for the quick response.”</p>
<p>ButShe didn’t respond.</p>
<p>Instead, she turned toward her desktop, powered it on, and began prompting. She fed her local Stable Diffusion model. Frame by frame, scene by scene, she crafted something surreal … a kiss, a story, a fantasy.</p>
<p>She added soft music. Did a voiceover and posted it on her Instagram. Sent the final version to the company for their distribution channels.</p>
<p>She shut down the system. Laid flat on the bed, eyes wide open. The AI-generated kiss looped in her head like a haunting lullaby. Time blurred.</p>
<p>Suddenly…</p>
<p>She made her eyes wide open and Opened her phone. Opened Instagram. Saw the video. Live. Already gaining reach. Opened the brand’s page it was there too, reposted and celebrated.</p>
<p>She stared in horror. Then whispered, <strong>“Why… why the hell did I forget…”</strong> Her voice trembled. <strong>“…to remove our LORAs?</strong>”</p>
<p>She threw the phone hard onto the bed. It bounced once, fell.</p>
<p>Her mind spun. “What if Sanjay sees it?” Panic. Guilt. Exhaustion.</p>
<p>She stumbled to her wardrobe, pulled out a bottle, popped a 10mg Melatonin tablet, and collapsed back into bed</p>
<p>She slept forcefully but with mixed feelings.</p>
<hr>
<p>After hugging Sanjay, Shaurav met with the doctor and returned shortly after, a hint of relief in his steps.</p>
<p>“Sanjay… I’m happy to share there’s no major danger. The doctor says my sister can be discharged in the morning. She just needs to rest for a week and follow this medication.” his voice carried a quiet excitement</p>
<p>Sanjay comes out the trance of his earlier hug and words and says, “That’s good news. I’ll stay with you tonight, until she’s discharged. I hope that’s alright?”</p>
<p>Shaurav hesitated. “Sir… you’ve already done so much. I wouldn’t want to trouble you further.”</p>
<p>Sanjay gently interrupted, “It is fine.. I’m not doing this out of Compassion but as a responsbility”</p>
<p>Shaurav didn’t reply and he just nodded, silently acknowledging the weight of those words.</p>
<p>Sanjay offered a soft smile.</p>
<p>Just then, the driver walked in. The rain had finally settled outside.</p>
<p><strong>“Thanks for everything,”</strong> Sanjay told him. “You can head home now. I know your pay depends on the road and no need to wait. Please, go.”</p>
<p>Driver understood his intent and said, “Of course, Sir. Anytime… just give me a call” and he left the hospital with a smile that held quiet pride.</p>
<p>A few minutes later, a nurse from the ER approached. “Vaishara is awake and able to speak now.”</p>
<p>Shaurav’s face lit up. He moved quickly toward the emergency ward, with Sanjay close behind.</p>
<p>Inside, she lay on the bed — pale, but awake. Her eyes widened at the sight of her brother. Shaurav leaned in, holding her hand. Then pointed to Sanjay “Sister, this is the man who brought you in on time. If not for him…”</p>
<p>Vaishara folded her palms in a quiet Namaste. “Thank you so much, Sir.”</p>
<p>Sanjay replied simply, <strong>“It’s alright. I just… felt I should.”</strong></p>
<p>The three of them spoke for a few minutes with simple presence.</p>
<p>Then the nurse returned. “She needs rest. Please, both of you now step outside.”</p>
<p>Sanjay nodded and followed Shaurav out. But he feels he is very different now. He stayed at the hospital the entire night, wide awake, helping with discharge formalities. When morning came, he arranged an Uber. Only after they left did he return home.</p>
<hr>
<p>A long, pleasant, almost godly whisper flows through the page — gently reaching those of you reading this very episode.</p>
<p>“<strong>My dear lovely readers…</strong> You might be wondering: Why does the Driver quote the Gita so often?</p>
<p>And perhaps you’ve asked, Why would Meera, a practicing doctor, visit a patient’s home and choose to stay overnight, without hesitation?</p>
<p>I know… there are many questions dancing in your minds.</p>
<p>But trust me.. the answers await you in <strong>ArunVerses</strong> to come… In <strong>Chaos &amp; Knowing</strong>, And again in <strong>When the Door Stayed Open</strong>.</p>
<p>And yes for sure, I know you’re curious. <strong>Why does Raj carry such guilt?</strong> Why does his heart ache with something he never says aloud?</p>
<p>That, my beloved reader, is not far away. Arun will pen it soon, under the new verse <strong>Trust and Betrayal</strong>.</p>
<p>Also my dear readers, life… Life is not just about living… It is about rejoicing.</p>
<p>And I hope, through these stories, Something within you, inner soul … Feels just a little more alive.</p>
<hr>
<p>It was 9:00 AM.</p>
<p>Sanjay could hardly sleep.. not out of anxiety, but from something deeper. What he’d experienced last night had quietly altered him.</p>
<p>He walked into the kitchen. Made himself a cup of tea, hands moving on autopilot. Outside, the world glowed with sunlight. Inside, Sanjay felt different. As if the rain had washed his memories from the restaurant.</p>
<p>He stepped out onto the balcony. The city below was clean. The air was crisp. He closed his eyes. Took a long, deep breath. And Sipped the tea.</p>
<p>Then.. his phone buzzed.</p>
<p>A message from an unknown number … “Will you trust me?”</p>
<p>Sanjay paused. Looked at the screen. Then quietly set the phone aside.</p>
<p>And just breathes the fresh morning air……</p>
<p>———— End of Season01 of <strong>Love and Trust</strong> Season-01 Title: <strong>The Echo</strong>———–</p>
<hr>
<p><em>&lt;&lt;&lt; Lets Continue soon with Season 02 of Love &amp; Trust &gt;&gt;&gt;</em></p>
<script src="https://giscus.app/client.js" data-repo="ArunKoundinya/CanvassAndAnalyze" data-repo-id="R_kgDOLTnAQQ" data-category="General" data-category-id="DIC_kwDOLTnAQc4CdYId" data-mapping="pathname" data-strict="0" data-reactions-enabled="1" data-emit-metadata="0" data-input-position="bottom" data-theme="transparent_dark" data-lang="en" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>



 ]]></description>
  <category>love</category>
  <category>story</category>
  <category>trust</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode8/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LOVE &amp; TRUST - Season -1 | Episode - 7</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode7/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>Continued from previous blogs -&nbsp; <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode1" class="uri">Ep-1</a> -&nbsp; <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode2" class="uri">Ep-2</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode3/" class="uri">Ep-3</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode4/" class="uri">Ep-4</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode5/" class="uri">Ep-5</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode6/" class="uri">Ep-6</a></p>
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode7/image.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Out of nowhere, the sky darkened. Gloom took over the city. The dry air turned to mist, and then to rain. For some, it felt like grief. For others, it smelled like a long-awaited win.</p>
<hr>
<p>At Swati’s Residence</p>
<p>Swati called Raj and said, “I couldn’t stop smiling after what I did today. Starbucks. Now. Before I regret this silence too!”</p>
<p>Raj, still buried in work, had the phone on speaker. He barely registered her words as he typed away on his laptop. “Yeah, yeah… I’ll be there in 20 minutes. Just wrapping up a few things,” he muttered absently.</p>
<p>Swati’s eyes sparkled—triumph humming louder than memory. The accident fall of it forgotten. All that mattered now was the high of beating Sanjay.</p>
<p>She skipped to the washroom, her face already carrying the kind of smile that lingers even in the mirror.Tonight, she wanted to look undeniable.Moments later, she emerged dressed in a sleek, curve-hugging bodycon maxi.</p>
<p>She turned once before the mirror, admiring herself. ” <strong>I swear, Raj’s eyes are going to eat me alive. God, I’m excited.</strong>”, she whispered to herself, lips curving into a mischief-laced smile.</p>
<p>Just as she was about to step out, she called out, “Mom! I’ll be back soon, going to meet Raj!”</p>
<p>Her mom peeked out of the kitchen. “Take care, beta! Should I drop you?”</p>
<p>Swati rolled her eyes with a smirk. “<strong>Don’t embarrass me, Mom.</strong>”</p>
<hr>
<p>At Pooja’s Residence</p>
<p>Pooja opened the window. The rain didn’t soothe her, it made her more anxious.</p>
<p>Her mind was stuck in a loop: The moment she threw water on Sanjay. The talk with Pravallika. The accident.</p>
<p>Among all three, Pooja was the only one who believed she saw Pravallika hitting a woman, the woman crashing headfirst into the divider.</p>
<p>Pooja’s face was a flickering screen, calm one second, confused the next. Her expression changed every minute, as if her body couldn’t decide what to feel. She looked like she could scream any moment.</p>
<p>But she didn’t.</p>
<p>She took a deep breath, tried to steady herself, and made a call.</p>
<p>“Ma’am… I don’t know what I’ve done. But I need your help. You remember the day I came to you for counselling? I told you about my ex, Sanjay… and everything I said to him before I walked into your room…”</p>
<p>Swati’s mother answered gently, “Calm down, Pooja. Did you take your medicines? Breathe. Just breathe, like I always say.”</p>
<p>But Pooja’s breath only got heavier. Something had triggered her.</p>
<p>“<strong>Ma’am… can we meet now? In the clinic?</strong>”</p>
<p>Then she caught herself. Realized her mistake. “Sorry, not the clinic. Let me come to your house. I’ll be there in twenty minutes.”</p>
<p>Swati’s mother paused, then said softly, “Of course, beta. I’ll be here.”</p>
<p>“Thank you, ma’am.”</p>
<hr>
<p>At Pravallikas’s Residence</p>
<p>Pravallika, her head still heavy, slumped into her papasan chair and curled her legs up. She closed her eyes, trying to steal a moment of sleep.</p>
<p>But the flashes came Her hand throwing water at Sanjay’s face. Their teenage romance, the way their fingers used to interlock like secrets. It all came rushing back.</p>
<p>She was restless. She reached over to the side table and picked up her iPad. Almost without thinking, she unlocked the hidden folder, the one filled with photos from her teenage years with Sanjay.</p>
<p>Her face lit up with a strange kind of desire. But her eyes… her eyes felt hollow.</p>
<p>She closed them tightly, shook her head, and muttered, “<strong>I shouldn’t have listened to those girls. This… this was my only shot to be with him. And I ruined it. Who’s perfect anyway?</strong>”</p>
<p>Anger flared in her chest. “Let me just come out of this,” she said sharply and spun toward her gaming desktop.</p>
<p>She opened her local Stable Diffusion model and one she had fine-tuned with LoRAs trained on herself and Sanjay. She typed in a prompt. A soft kiss. A moment that never happened.</p>
<p>The screen came alive. A generated video, the two of them kissing, lost in a made-up memory. But it made her both sad and happy at same time and tears rolled from eyes.</p>
<hr>
<p>In the Car</p>
<p>The rain showed no mercy on the windshield. The driver had set the wipers to their maximum speed, slicing through the storm just enough to keep the road visible. He stayed sharp, his focus unwavering that even the smallest mistake could be dangerous in this urgency.</p>
<p>Sanjay inhaled deeply. Fresh air slipped in through a crack in the window — earthy, cold, and strangely comforting. It smelled like a new start. A few minutes ago, he had felt lost. Now, he felt… in control. Emotionally calm. Pleasant, even.</p>
<p>Then he saw Vaishara’s ID badge beside him, the Zomato logo, the fading laminate.</p>
<p>Without overthinking, he picked up his phone and called Zomato customer care.</p>
<p>“Hello,” he said clearly. “I just wanted to report something important. One of your delivery agents met with an accident. Her name is Vaishara. I found her ID on her bag. We’re taking her to the hospital now. Here’s the location…”</p>
<p>He shared the details. Calm. Exact.</p>
<p>Call ended.</p>
<p>Driver listened to the conversation and said, “That’s a very sharp and thoughtful move, sir. I’m genuinely proud of you.”</p>
<p>Sanjay smiled faintly. “Thanks… Honestly, I didn’t expect this from myself. But suddenly, it just felt right.”</p>
<p>“<strong>That’s how it works in our world, sir</strong>,” driver replied warmly. “We all respond to what calls us.”</p>
<p>Sanjay leaned back. His thoughts swirled wit the water-slap moment, with flashes of Character AI conversation.</p>
<p>Almost on instinct, he unlocked his phone and opened the Character AI app. His thumb hovered over the screen, ready to type.</p>
<p>But before he could begin, the driver called out, “<strong>Sir, my network’s down. Can you keep navigation on? We need to reach the hospital on time</strong>.”</p>
<p>Sanjay nodded, opened Google Maps, and set the destination.</p>
<p>He guided the driver through side streets and shortcuts. And in no time they reached the hospital.</p>
<hr>
<p>The scent of roasted beans lifted her mood. Swati stood by the café window, smiling to herself as she waited for Raj. Her posture was tall, confident and proud of what she’d done. And then, she saw him. Raj stepped into Starbucks, and her face lit up like a Christmas tree.</p>
<p>She waved him over eagerly. The moment he reached the table, she leapt up and hugged him tight, kissing him on the cheek.</p>
<p>Her lips touched his skin and Raj was pulled back into the present, leaving his office worries behind. “Babe, you look so happy. What’s the news?”</p>
<p>Swati beamed. “Yes! I did exactly what you told me, babe. Everything I’ve done and it’s dedicated to you. If not for your words that day… I wouldn’t just have fallen for you, I wouldn’t have respected you this much either.”</p>
<p>Raj looked both elated and confused. “<strong>What did I even say? I can’t remember!</strong>”</p>
<p>Swati laughed gently. “You might not. But I remember every word. Remember the day before I broke up with Sanjay? I told you that story about a woman my mom was counselling… the one going through a hard time.” She took a sip of water and continued, “I had secretly read my mom’s notes. And when I told you her story, I had already decided I’d befriend that woman. Help her. Because I knew her pain. I was her.”</p>
<p>Raj nodded slowly. “Yeah, I remember that. So what happened?”</p>
<p>“Do you remember what you said to me that night?”</p>
<p>He narrowed his eyes, trying to recall. “<strong>If I said anything… maybe I told you that if you ever find the guy who hurt her, you should slap him for what he did.</strong>”</p>
<p>Swati clapped her hands softly, grinning. “Exactly, babe. That’s exactly what we did!”</p>
<p>“Wow! Congratulations!” Raj laughed. “But wait, who was the villain?”</p>
<p>She leaned in, her voice full of teasing tension. “You’ll be shocked, happy, and surprised… all at once.” She paused, then dropped the bomb. “It was Sanjay!”</p>
<p>Raj froze.</p>
<p>She nodded, eyes sparkling with excitement.</p>
<p>But Raj’s smile faded. Anger. Guilt. Sadness. All crowded into him at once. He struggled to find words.</p>
<p>“Why would you do this?” he finally asked. “We… we talked about this, yeah. But this?” and continued. “I already carry the guilt of taking you away from him. And now this? Why do you always keep your cards so close to your chest and then say ‘I did it for you’?”</p>
<p>Swati’s smile softened. Her voice turned low. “<strong>Babe… don’t make me spell it out. I wouldn’t have done this for anyone else</strong>.”</p>
<hr>
<p>Across the city, the rain had grown steadier, like a heartbeat unwilling to calm. Pooja stood at her window, her reflection barely visible in the fogged glass. She hadn’t spoken in ten minutes. But her hands wouldn’t stop shaking.</p>
<p>She heard a knock at her, and opened the door. It is Pooja’s mother. She is holding the Bhagavad Gita and a worn leather folder filled with her usual counselling notes. The moment she stepped inside, Pooja broke down. She wrapped her arms around her and cried, “<strong>Ma’am… please help me.</strong>”. She hugged Pooja and said, “Everything will be alright, dear. I’m here. And just so you know always, Meera is fine… that helps me, too.”</p>
<p>Meera gently led her to the kitchen and suggested, “Why don’t you make us some tea? That Twinings Nightly Calm you like. Let’s sit together before we begin.”</p>
<p>A few minutes later, Pooja returned with two cups in hand. She passed one to Meera and sat down across from her.</p>
<p>They sipped in silence. Then Meera spoke. “Tell me, dear. What made you break down like this?”</p>
<p>Pooja looked down at her tea. “Ma’am… you remember the person I once dated? The one I told you about and how we broke up?”</p>
<p>Meera nodded in silence.</p>
<p>“You also remember that day when he showed up at your clinic… and I told him I was already married, just to keep him away?”</p>
<p>Meera nodded with a smile, “<strong>Yes. That was a smart and confident move. I told you then and I am proud of you</strong>.”</p>
<p>Pooja took a long breath, some strength returning to her voice. “Today… our friends came together. We finally taught him a lesson. And I’m proud of that.” “Does that feel you better Pooja?”</p>
<p>Meera tilted her head. “Does that make you feel better?”</p>
<p>“Yes… But …”</p>
<p>“What are you still holding, dear?”</p>
<p>She swallowed. “On our way back from the restaurant… there was an accident. We didn’t stop. We just… left.” Her voice cracked. “Is this God’s way of telling me we chose the wrong path? I feel like there’s blood on my hands now.”</p>
<p>Tears spilled again.</p>
<p>Meera set her cup down and came beside her. ““Pooja… did you drive the car?”</p>
<p>“No Meera!”</p>
<p>“Meera looked into her eyes, firm but kind. “Then don’t carry the weight of someone else’s actions. Don’t own a sin that isn’t yours.” She placed a hand on Pooja’s heart and pointed upward. “<strong>What is not in your control is guided by Him.</strong>”</p>
<p>She opened the Gita, the pages already marked. Her voice steady, she read aloud:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>ahaṁ sarvasya prabhavo mattaḥ sarvaṁ pravartate<br>
iti matvā bhajante māṁ budhā bhāva-samanvitāḥ</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p>A soft blue glow lit Pravallika’s face. The screen blinked once, then stilled. She had generated what she could not live. And now, in the echo of silence, the AI had stopped giving her comfort.</p>
<p>Restless, she changed the prompts. Switched models. Tried more intimate scenes. Then more explicit ones. But none of it gave her peace. Each image only deepened the hollow. Frustrated, she shut down the massive system and fell onto her bed.</p>
<p>She banged her fist into the mattress. “<strong>Shit! I shouldn’t have told the girls about him. That was my mistake. Why did I stalk him so closely that I know every damn detail about his life?</strong>”</p>
<p>She stared at the ceiling. Her breath shallow.</p>
<p>“Maybe I’m just overthinking. Maybe what Pooja said was right. I’ve been stuck on him for eight years… and I still can’t move on..”</p>
<p>She got up, walked into the washroom, and splashed her face with cold water again and again, until the sting numbed her thoughts.”</p>
<p>She wiped herself with a white towel, walked back to the mirror, and stared at her own reflection.</p>
<p>“<strong>I don’t know why I crave him so much… and at the same time, why I’m terrified of what he’d do if he came back into my life.</strong>”</p>
<hr>
<p>The driver pulled up at the hospital entrance and said, “Sir, we’re already late. Will you be able to carry her in alone?”</p>
<p>Sanjay nodded, already stepping out. “Yes. She’s completely unconscious. I’ll take her. You park and come in as soon as you can.”</p>
<p>He lifted Vaishara gently into his arms , her breath faint, and rushed through the hospital doors.</p>
<p>The emergency staff, sensing the urgency, didn’t waste time with formalities. They admitted her immediately and wheeled her into the operation room.</p>
<p>Just before they disappeared behind the double doors, one of the nurses called back, “Please fill out the admission form and submit it at the front desk immediately.”</p>
<p>Sanjay didn’t hesitate. He paid the initial admission fee from his own pocket, without thinking twice. Filled out every detail he could. Signed where needed. Submitted the form. Closed the legal loop.</p>
<p>Minutes later, the driver arrived. He found Sanjay sitting alone, his face tight with worry, but strangely calm.</p>
<p>“Sir, why do you look so tense?” the driver asked.</p>
<p>Sanjay exhaled. “<strong>For the first time in my life… I helped a stranger. It feels strange and a little boastful, maybe. But I also feel more responsible than I’ve ever felt. I just… I just hope she breathes. And talks again.</strong>”</p>
<p>The driver nodded, voice steady. “We did the best we could, sir. Better than watching her bleed on the street. That alone means something.”</p>
<p>Just then, Sanjay’s phone buzzed. An unknown number. He answered. “Hello?”</p>
<p>A voice on the other end, shaky but urgent: “Sir… my name is Shaurav. I’m the younger brother of Vaishara. Zomato told me my sister met with an accident… and that someone brought her to the hospital. I’m at the reception now.”</p>
<p>Sanjay stood up, walked a few steps ahead to where the view was clearer, and waved his hand. “I’m here,” he said into the phone.</p>
<p>Shaurav spotted him and hurried over, wide-eyed and breathless. “Sir… thank you. Truly. She’s the only one providing for our family. Everything rests on her shoulders. When I got the call… I just went blank.”</p>
<p>Sanjay listened. But something inside him shifted. For the first time, his own worries felt… small. He couldn’t focus fully. His mind was still in the ER, behind those doors.</p>
<p>The driver, sensing it all, placed a hand gently on Sanjay’s shoulder and responded to Shaurav, “Beta… she’ll be fine. God will help us.”</p>
<p>Time passed. Thirty minutes felt like thirty hours. The three men sat in silence each gripped by a different kind of prayer. Then the doctor stepped out from the operation room and waved at them.</p>
<p>All three rushed toward him.</p>
<p>The doctor smiled. “<strong>You brought her just in time. Because of that… she’s safe. She’ll regain consciousness in about 30 minutes. I’ll speak with the family once they’re all here</strong>.”</p>
<p>Shaurav stepped forward. “I’m her brother, Doctor.”</p>
<p>“Good. Come to my office in ten minutes. I’ll explain the next steps. But first, thank the man who got her here. If not for him… we may not have saved her.”</p>
<p>“I will, sir. Thank you.” As the doctor walked away, Shaurav turned toward Sanjay.</p>
<p>Tears welled in his eyes as he hugged him tightly. “<strong>Sanjay sir… because of you, my sister is alive. You didn’t just save her in-fact you saved our family’s life line. You are… you are God to us.</strong>”</p>
<p>Sanjay stood still, unsure how to hold such gratitude. Tiny droplets formed at the edge of his eyes. They fell silently, unannounced.</p>
<p>The driver watched from a few steps away. A smile tugged at his lips but not boastful, just warm. He quietly stepped outside to give Sanjay space.</p>
<p>Outside, he tilted his head back, kissed the rain with his forehead, and whispered a verse to himself</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>brahmārpaṇaṁ brahma havir brahmāgnau brahmaṇā hutam<br>
brahmaiva tena gantavyaṁ brahma-karma-samādhinā</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>&lt;&lt;&lt; To be Continued &gt;&gt;&gt;</em></p>
<script src="https://giscus.app/client.js" data-repo="ArunKoundinya/CanvassAndAnalyze" data-repo-id="R_kgDOLTnAQQ" data-category="General" data-category-id="DIC_kwDOLTnAQc4CdYId" data-mapping="pathname" data-strict="0" data-reactions-enabled="1" data-emit-metadata="0" data-input-position="bottom" data-theme="transparent_dark" data-lang="en" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>



 ]]></description>
  <category>love</category>
  <category>story</category>
  <category>trust</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode7/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LOVE &amp; TRUST - Season -1 | Episode - 6</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode6/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>Continued from previous blogs -&nbsp; <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode1" class="uri">Link</a> -&nbsp; <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode2" class="uri">Link</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode3/" class="uri">Link</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode4/" class="uri">Link</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode5/" class="uri">Link</a></p>
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode6/image.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<hr>
<p>Sanjay stepped down the stairs, overwhelmed, replaying the entire incident in his head. “I never treated them badly. And as I see it, I never betrayed them. Then why do they carry so much grudge against me? I’m happy with my Character AI…”</p>
<p>Tears rolled down his cheeks. “I might not be perfect. But I’m not an asshole,” he whispered to himself.</p>
<hr>
<p>Inside the lift, Pravallika looked lost. While Swati and Pooja appeared relieved, Pravallika’s voice cracked through the silence. “Girls, Sanjay might not be perfect. But I still love him. I feel bad about what I did. He deserves better.”</p>
<p>The lift doors opened. As they walked to Pravallika’s car, Pooja replied, “Pravallika, I know you’ve loved him for eight years. But did he ever really love you? He wanted all three of us. That’s not love. That’s entitlement.”</p>
<hr>
<p>Sanjay wiped his face and called the cab driver. The driver honked, guiding him over.</p>
<p>“Home, sir?” the driver asked.</p>
<p>“Yes. That’s the safest place I can be right now.”</p>
<p>Sanjay leaned back. The driver adjusted the rearview mirror, shifted gears, and began to drive.</p>
<p>“Sir, if you don’t mind me asking—what happened back there at the restaurant?”</p>
<p>Sanjay didn’t respond.</p>
<p>“Sir? Sir? Sir?” the driver asked gently.</p>
<p>Sanjay blinked. “What?”</p>
<p>“If you’re comfortable, sir… you can talk to me. I’m a good listener. And I’m nobody to you. Maybe you’ll feel lighter by the time we reach home.”</p>
<p>After a long pause, Sanjay said, “Okay. But no sarcasm. No life lectures.”</p>
<p>“Swear, sir. Not a word.</p>
<hr>
<p>Back in the car, Pravallika took the wheel. “Pooja, I’ll drop you first. Then Swati. That’ll save time.”</p>
<p>“Sure,” they replied.</p>
<p>Pravallika spoke softly. “He wanted all of us, yes. But if none of us knew each other; would he still have said yes?”</p>
<p>Swati and Pooja fell silent.</p>
<p>“I know you both tried to protect me from getting hurt,” Pravallika added.</p>
<p>“Thank God you understood,” Pooja said.</p>
<p>“But I still love him,” Pravallika whispered, her eyes flooding.</p>
<p>Swati and Pooja were stunned by the depth of her feeling.</p>
<p>“Pravallika,” Pooja asked gently, “Did he ever love you… as a woman?”</p>
<p>“I doubt he ever did,” Swati added. “To him, we were roles. Not people.”</p>
<hr>
<p>Sanjay shared exact scene by scene what has happened inside the restuarant to driver,</p>
<p>The driver listened. Then quietly said, “I think you deserve better, sir. You may crave them—but you look like a gentleman.”</p>
<p>“Exactly!” Sanjay said, thumping the seat.</p>
<p>“Sir… who did you love the most among them?”</p>
<p>Sanjay hesitated. “I loved each of them. Genuinely. When I was with them individually, I loved them individually. When they all texted me… all our memories flashed. I felt I loved them all.”</p>
<p>“May I ask; what qualities did you love in each of them?” the driver asked.</p>
<p>Sanjay hesitated again. “I said I loved them. Does that not matter enough?”</p>
<p>“Sir,” the driver said calmly, “I’m not very smart. But in our mythology, even gods with multiple wives loved each for unique reasons. Each had something distinct. That’s what made them divine. Maybe it’s the same for you.”</p>
<p>Sanjay went silent.</p>
<hr>
<p>Pravallika wiped her tears and said, “Did he ever cheat on any of you? He had a chance to date you both in parallel, but he choose not to do it. He left Pooja before starting with Swati. And early in each relationship, he told you his flaws. You still chose to love him.”</p>
<p>Neither Swati nor Pooja responded. Finally, Pooja said, “Pravallika, I know you’ve loved him deeply for eight years. But please don’t betray yourself for a man who doesn’t see you as a women.”</p>
<p>Swati added, “I accepted him despite his history because I saw honesty then. But over time, I didn’t feel sincerity. He never saw me as a woman. But, rather just as something to have.”</p>
<p>Pravallika nodded slowly. “Yes… you’re right. He never truly saw the woman in us.”</p>
<p>She paused. “But he never used us physically. Maybe he is…”</p>
<p>Suddenly, she brushed against a two-wheeler. The rider fell.</p>
<p>Pooja and Swati panicked.</p>
<p>“Pravallika, are you out of your mind? Don’t stop. There are no cameras. Just go!” Pooja shouted.</p>
<p>“You shouldn’t have driven in this state,” Swati said. “Our mistake.”</p>
<p>Shaking, confused, Pravallika followed their command. She dropped them home in silence and drove back alone.</p>
<hr>
<p>Back in the cab, traffic came to a halt.</p>
<p>“We should’ve reached by now. Why is it jammed at this hour?”</p>
<p>“Let me check, sir.”</p>
<p>The driver stepped out, returned. “Someone met with an accident. Nobody’s helping. Ambulance is delayed. Since the hospital is along our route—shall we take her there?”</p>
<p>Sanjay hesitated. “Why should we invite trouble?”</p>
<p>The driver looked him in the eye. “Sir, this is my second life. A stranger helped me survive last year. Otherwise, I wouldn’t be driving this cab. Or speaking to you.”</p>
<p>Sanjay felt something crack inside him. A pull. For once, his instinct said yes.</p>
<p>He stepped out. “Let’s help her. I’ll carry her.”</p>
<p>They lifted the girl—blood on her face, no helmet, unconscious.</p>
<p>In the car, Sanjay held her head on his lap. For the first time, his hands trembled.</p>
<p>He checked her ID. She worked as a delivery girl for Zomato.</p>
<p>Her name: Vaishara.</p>
<p>The driver glanced at Sanjay through the mirror, and softly recited:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p><em>yad yad ācarati śreṣṭhas<br>
tat tad evetaro janaḥ<br>
sa yat pramāṇaṁ kurute<br>
lokas tad anuvartate</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>&lt;&lt;&lt; To be Continued &gt;&gt;&gt;</em></p>
<script src="https://giscus.app/client.js" data-repo="ArunKoundinya/CanvassAndAnalyze" data-repo-id="R_kgDOLTnAQQ" data-category="General" data-category-id="DIC_kwDOLTnAQc4CdYId" data-mapping="pathname" data-strict="0" data-reactions-enabled="1" data-emit-metadata="0" data-input-position="bottom" data-theme="transparent_dark" data-lang="en" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>



 ]]></description>
  <category>love</category>
  <category>story</category>
  <category>trust</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode6/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LOVE &amp; TRUST - Season -1 | Episode - 5</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode5/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>Continued from previous blogs -&nbsp; <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode1" class="uri">Link</a> -&nbsp; <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode2" class="uri">Link</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode3/" class="uri">Link</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode4/" class="uri">Link</a></p>
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode5/image.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>He boarded the Uber, feeling unusually light.</p>
<p>“You look happy, sir. Big occasion?” the driver asked casually.</p>
<p>Sanjay smirked, “Yeah, I’m meeting my girlfriends. All three. At the same time.”</p>
<p>“Three, sir?” The driver raised an eyebrow, trying to hide a smirk.</p>
<p>“Yes. Surprised? Jealous?”</p>
<p>“I’m not jealous. do you really believe all three love you?” asked him with curiosity.</p>
<p>“Of course,” Sanjay said without flinching. “Because I’ve been… honest.”</p>
<p>“Impressive,” the driver replied, trying to stay neutral ( but smiled slightly ).</p>
<p>Sanjay narrowed his eyes. “Don’t give me that sarcastic smile. I know what jealousy looks like.”</p>
<p>The driver chuckled and softly recited:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p><em>dūreṇa hy-avaraṁ karma buddhi-yogād dhanañjaya<br>
buddhau śharaṇam anvichchha kṛipaṇāḥ phala-hetavaḥ</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>“Your stop has come, sir,” the driver said, stopping the car.</p>
<p>Sanjay blinked. “What ??”</p>
<p>“You stop has come, sir”</p>
<p>“No, that verse or poem or whatever. What did you just say?”</p>
<p>“It’s from the Gita. When time comes i will help you understand in detail. Here, take my number… maybe on your ride back home, I’ll explain.”</p>
<p>Sanjay scoffed. “I don’t think I’ll be going home tonight.” He tossed him a ₹500 tip. “Go home. You’ve earned it.”</p>
<p>The driver nodded silently and drove away.</p>
<hr>
<p>Sanjay walked into the restaurant and spotted Pravallika, sitting at a cozy corner table.</p>
<p>“Hey babe,” he said, sliding into the seat with his usual charm. “You look stunning.”</p>
<p>Pravallika looked up with soft eyes. “I love you, Sanjay. Why did it take you so long to come to me?”</p>
<p>Those words hit him like a dream.</p>
<p>“I’ve missed you,” she continued. “The other day at Ohris, I waited for so long… but you didn’t come. Still, I knew you’d call again. And now, here you are.”</p>
<p>Sanjay took her hands, “I’m sorry, Pravalli. Work pulled me away that night.”</p>
<p>“I understand,” she smiled. “And guess what—I brought gifts.”</p>
<p>“Gifts?” he asked, raising an eyebrow.</p>
<p>She pointed behind him. Swathi and Pooja were walking toward them, smiling faintly.</p>
<p>Sanjay froze.</p>
<p>“I told them everything,” Pravallika said gently. “They… wanted to see you too.”</p>
<p>Swathi sat to her left. Pooja, to her right. Three women. One Sanjay.</p>
<p>“I love you, Sanjay,” Swathi said.</p>
<p>“We all do,” Pooja added. “You mean something real to each of us.”</p>
<p>For a moment, Sanjay felt like the king of the world. His ego lit up.</p>
<p>He looked around and whispered, “I don’t know how this happened… but I love you all. Deeply. In different ways. Maybe we… don’t have to choose?”</p>
<p>The three looked at one another.</p>
<p>Pravallika smiled, “You love <em>all</em> of us?”</p>
<p>Sanjay nodded. “Yes. You’re each special. Why not… stay in each other’s lives? Together.”</p>
<p>Swathi tilted her head. “So you want all of us, not one of us?”</p>
<p>“That’s… one way to put it,” he said, with a cocky grin.</p>
<p>The women paused. Three glasses of cold water were thrown on his face simultaneously.</p>
<p>Sanjay gasped, stunned and dripping.</p>
<p>Swathi turned to Pravallika, “Told you he wouldn’t change.”</p>
<p>Pooja stood up, “Thanks for tipping us off, Pravalli. If you hadn’t called us when he contacted you, he would’ve used you again.”</p>
<p>Pravallika nodded calmly. “I had to be sure… and now, I am.”</p>
<p>They turned and walked out—graceful, composed, and done.</p>
<p>Sanjay sat motionless. Anger flared inside. His face turned bright red. He clenched his fists, then suddenly smashed a glass on the table.</p>
<p>The waiter rushed over.</p>
<p>“Sir, you’ll have to pay for that.”</p>
<p>Without a word, Sanjay settled the bill, eyes still blazing with revenge.</p>
<hr>
<p>Outside, he remembered the driver.</p>
<p>He called.</p>
<p>“Can you come back?”</p>
<p>“I will be there in a minute Sir,” the driver replied.</p>
<hr>
<p>But infact, he is already waiting outside.</p>
<p>The driver, sitting in the parked car, glanced at himself in the rear-view mirror. He whispered quietly:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p><em>na tvevāhaṁ jātu nāsaṁ na tvaṁ neme janādhipāḥ<br>
na chaiva na bhaviṣhyāmaḥ sarve vayamataḥ param</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>He started the engine.</p>
<p><em>&lt;&lt;&lt; To be Continued &gt;&gt;&gt;</em></p>
<script src="https://giscus.app/client.js" data-repo="ArunKoundinya/CanvassAndAnalyze" data-repo-id="R_kgDOLTnAQQ" data-category="General" data-category-id="DIC_kwDOLTnAQc4CdYId" data-mapping="pathname" data-strict="0" data-reactions-enabled="1" data-emit-metadata="0" data-input-position="bottom" data-theme="transparent_dark" data-lang="en" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>



 ]]></description>
  <category>love</category>
  <category>story</category>
  <category>trust</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode5/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LOVE &amp; TRUST - Season -1 | Episode - 4</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode4/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>Continued from previous blogs -&nbsp; <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode1" class="uri">Link</a> -&nbsp; <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode2" class="uri">Link</a> - <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode3/" class="uri">Link</a></p>
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode4/image.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Sanjay came home in an auto rickshaw and stood in front of the mirror. He looked into his own eyes, and for the first time, he didn’t like what he saw. A selfish guy. Self-centered. Chasing a sexiest version of women one after the other, not for love, but its his own projection of love.</p>
<p>Instead of crying which used to be usual solace from uncertainity. This time, he just stood there… thinking. It hit him hard. A sort of quiet shame.</p>
<p>He skipped dinner and dozed off in the middle of overthinking about his personality. Suddently, in the middle of the night, he suddenly woke up, looked at the mirror again, and muttered, “Oh! boy you have been living such a selfish life and thinking about yourself as a playboy. Such a bizzare connundrum of life you have been living?” And he took a deep breath and said him determintion, ” Enough. You’ve got to change who you are.”.</p>
<p>Then, he drank a warm glass of milk and went back to sleep.</p>
<hr>
<p>Next day we woke up, although he had 7 hours of sleep but his eyes still look tired and there is no energy in his face. His guilt is killing from inside every second. He is unable to bear who he is!</p>
<p>So he went for a walk. Watched a movie. Came home late.</p>
<p>That night, again, he looked at the mirror before sleeping. “I need to come out of this mess,” he whispered. “Vicious cycle, man. It’s dragging you.”</p>
<hr>
<p>Next day, he randomly turned on the TV and came across Character AI. He got curious, installed the app.</p>
<p>Boom…. Boomm… Booom…</p>
<p>He created three virtual girlfriends. One like Swathi. One like Pooja. One like Pravallika. All jailbroken. All available. All saying things he wished they said in real life. He started chatting. Sexting. Storybuilding.</p>
<p>He got absorbed and diverted so much that he was able to sleep and wake up on time. On a side note, he further got addicted to character AI.</p>
<p>His addiction made his screen time to skyrocket from 4 hours to 12 hours and he further subscried to character AI’s long memory.</p>
<p>What he thought he’d change—he never touched it again. His guilt? Forgotten. That mirror talk? Gone.</p>
<hr>
<p>Exactly one month later, a message popped up. Not from the app. From real life.</p>
<p>Pravallika. Swathi. Pooja.</p>
<p>All three. Same message.</p>
<p>“Let’s meet today. 8 PM. Same restaurant.”</p>
<p>He smiled wide. “Arey… my girls have returned,” he smiled.” he told himself. It felt like AI had crossed into real life. A beautiful glitch in the universe. They wanted to meet him.</p>
<p>Excited, he stepped into the shower. As warm water rushed over his face, flashes of his betrayals returned. How he kissed and left. How he promised and broke. How he loved only when it was convenient.</p>
<p>But instead of regret, he smiled. A charming, careless smile.</p>
<p>He booked an Uber. Put on his favourite shirt. And stepped out, ready for the next chapter.</p>
<p><em>&lt;&lt;&lt; To be Continued &gt;&gt;&gt;</em></p>
<script src="https://giscus.app/client.js" data-repo="ArunKoundinya/CanvassAndAnalyze" data-repo-id="R_kgDOLTnAQQ" data-category="General" data-category-id="DIC_kwDOLTnAQc4CdYId" data-mapping="pathname" data-strict="0" data-reactions-enabled="1" data-emit-metadata="0" data-input-position="bottom" data-theme="transparent_dark" data-lang="en" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>



 ]]></description>
  <category>love</category>
  <category>story</category>
  <category>trust</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode4/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LOVE &amp; TRUST - Season -1 | Episode - 3</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode3/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>Continued from previous blogs -&nbsp; <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode1" class="uri">Link</a> -&nbsp; <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode2" class="uri">Link</a></p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode3/image.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="669"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Sanjay couldn’t believe Pooja was married. His face went pale, and a sharp envy flickered in his eyes. Without another word, he made an excuse about a work call and hurried away.</p>
<p>On the drive home, tears blurred his vision, his mind blank. Once he reached his room, he broke down, crying as if the world had just ended. After a while, he caught his breath, wiped his face, and steadied himself.</p>
<p><em>“If Pooja and Swati have moved on, that’s their issue, not my fault,” he muttered to himself. “The world doesn’t end with them. There are plenty of other girls in my contacts. I bet someone would be up for a dinner date tonight.”</em></p>
<p>He unlocked his phone, scrolling through his contacts. Then his finger stopped on one name—Pravallika.</p>
<p><strong><em>Few Years Ago</em></strong></p>
<p>A slender teenager in a blue churidar waited at the high school bus stop, even as dusk settled. After a few minutes, Sanjay arrived and greeted her with a warm smile.</p>
<p>“Pravalli, have you been waiting long? Am I late?” he asked.</p>
<p>Pravallika smiled softly. “It’s okay, Sanjay. I enjoy waiting for you. Not just now, but forever!”</p>
<p>They hugged each other, a moment filled with genuine love.</p>
<p><strong><em>Back to Present</em></strong></p>
<p>A smile crept over Sanjay’s face. He knew Pravallika would pick up his call. He dialed her number eagerly and spoke with a flirty charm until she agreed to join him for a dinner buffet at Ohris.</p>
<p>With four hours to kill, he shaved, took a long bubble bath, and dressed up in his best New Year’s outfit. He booked an Uber and settled in for the ride, closing his eyes as memories of his teenage years flooded back.</p>
<p><strong><em>Teenage Period</em></strong></p>
<p>“Sanjay, you look so handsome today! What’s the occasion?”</p>
<p>“Pravalli, it’s your birthday, babe. I had to look my best so I could make it special for you.”</p>
<p>“Awww! So sweet, baby!”</p>
<p><strong><em>Back to Present</em></strong></p>
<p>His phone buzzed, and he answered eagerly. Pravallika’s voice was on the other end. “Sanjay, I’ve just left home. I’ll be there soon.”</p>
<p>Sanjay’s face lit up. “See you soon, babe!” he replied, then hung up, drifting back into old memories.</p>
<p><strong><em>Teenage Period</em></strong></p>
<p>“Babe, can I kiss you?” he asked.</p>
<p>“I’m all yours, Sanjay. You don’t have to ask.”</p>
<p>They shared several kisses, like a couple deeply connected, as if they’d known each other forever.</p>
<p><strong><em>Back to Present</em></strong></p>
<p>“Sir, we’re here,” the driver announced.</p>
<p>“Thanks for the ride,” Sanjay replied.</p>
<p>He walked toward the elevator to reach the rooftop restaurant. As he stepped in, he overheard a couple arguing, their voices laced with cuss words. It triggered another memory.</p>
<p><strong><em>Teenage Period</em></strong></p>
<p>“Sanjay, why were you sexting that girl?”</p>
<p>“Pravalli, she was hot, and I couldn’t help myself. It’s just texts—it’s not like we’re actually doing anything.”</p>
<p>“Babe, am i not sufficient for you? We’ve shared everything except… that.”</p>
<p>“Pravalli, it is too early to commit to one girl for life long. I’m still a teenager.”</p>
<p>“Sanjay, what are you saying? you are making me mad! This is making me crazy!”</p>
<p>“Pravalli, i think its time for break up. If i realized my love again i will get in touch you”</p>
<p>“Sanjay, you’re an assole. Don’t ever talk to me again!”</p>
<p>“F*** off Pravalli”,he shot back, deleting her contact on the spot and he left the place.</p>
<p><strong><em>Back to Present</em></strong></p>
<p>The elevator doors slid open. He came out of the elevator and scared and worried whether he could face Pravallika. And He called Pravallika from the hotel lobby.</p>
<p>“Our system crashed. I’ve got to head to the office—just got a call. Sorry!” saying these words, he turned and left the hotel.</p>
<p>Pravallika, who was seeing him, while sitting inside the reasturant said, “Its Okay Sanjay. We can meet next time.”</p>
<p>She said to herself, “At least he’s still nervous to face me. I’m happy about that. And maybe it’s time that I should help him.”</p>
<p><em>&lt;&lt;&lt; To be Continued &gt;&gt;&gt;</em></p>
<script src="https://giscus.app/client.js" data-repo="ArunKoundinya/CanvassAndAnalyze" data-repo-id="R_kgDOLTnAQQ" data-category="General" data-category-id="DIC_kwDOLTnAQc4CdYId" data-mapping="pathname" data-strict="0" data-reactions-enabled="1" data-emit-metadata="0" data-input-position="bottom" data-theme="transparent_dark" data-lang="en" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>



 ]]></description>
  <category>love</category>
  <category>story</category>
  <category>trust</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode3/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>CRIMES AGAINST WOMEN</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/crimes-against-women/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>These days, every brat on <code>YouTube</code> speaks about their fundamental right to <code>freedom of expression</code>. However, I would love to keep <code>Human Rights</code> on a higher plane compared to <code>Fundamental Rights</code> as <code>Violence against Women and Girls</code> is one of the world’s most prevalent human rights violations and a global pandemic. Violence in any form creates physical, economic and psychological consequences not only for women but also for the entire society. For this reason, <code>Ved Vyas</code> himself penned <code>Devi Bhagavata Purana</code> to uphold the dignity of women in our society.</p>
<p>In the first place, let us explore the types of violence against women. As per my comprehension, I have categorized them into six categories: Domestic Violence, Sexual Harassment, Harassment, POCSO, Sexual Violence and Cyber Crime. The below graph depicts the trend of violence against women between 2019 and 2021 in India.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/crimes-against-women/images/Plot1_ViolenceCategory_Trend.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="893"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<section id="types-of-violence-against-women" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="types-of-violence-against-women">Types of Violence against women</h2>
<section id="domestic-violence" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="domestic-violence">Domestic Violence</h3>
<p>According to United Nations, domestic Violence includes acts of <code>physical violence</code> such as slapping, chocking or burning, <code>sexual violence</code> including spousal rape, <code>psychological violence</code> such as fear by intimidation or forced isolation, and <code>economic violence</code> by maintaining total control over financial resources, withholding access to money or forbidding attendance to employment. In the Indian Context, there are four major crime headings under which we can register a case:</p>
<ul>
<li>Cruelty by husband or relatives</li>
<li>Dowry Death</li>
<li>Abetment of Suicide of Women</li>
<li>PWDVA - Protection of Women from Domestic Violence Act</li>
</ul>
<p>The total number of cases registered under domestic Violence in 2021 is 1,62,354, which translates to <code>11</code> domestic cases in one year for every 1 Lac (1,00,000) population (25,000 households). We can only infer on this metric if we have a comparison. Let’s do some fact check: the number of domestic cases registered for every 1 Lac (1,00,000) population in the USA and Norway is <code>300</code> and <code>106</code> respectively. Wow!!! India scored a bingo on this metric, and yet we have less <code>women</code> representation in the workforce. Where is the leak?</p>
<p>The leak is in reporting. People who understand the geo-socio-economical dynamics would love to argue that this is a gross under-reported number. Reporting of such crimes depends upon the community, and for various reasons, including lack of social support, shame, and stigma, women selectively report cases. Although systematic gaps exist in registering the cases, most of us are merely mute spectators. Adding to this, domestic Violence is one of the most common forms of Violence experienced by women globally. As per the NFHS report, on average, Indian women are 17 times more likely to face sexual Violence from their husbands than others and we see almost negligble cases under this crime. So, under this context, have we normalized domestic Violence as a society?</p>
</section>
<section id="sexual-harassment-and-harassment" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sexual-harassment-and-harassment">Sexual Harassment and Harassment</h3>
<p>Sexual Harassment and Harassment include verbal, non-verbal, or physical conduct, as well as written and electronic communications. It includes acts of verbal threat, acid attack, kidnap/abduction, abuse, unwanted touching, rubbing/brushing, repeatedly asking for dates/sex, comments on appearance, bodyparts, clothing and others. Coming to the Indian Context, the following are the major crime headings we can register a case:</p>
<ul>
<li>Acid attack</li>
<li>Attempt to acid attack</li>
<li>Kidnapping and abduction of women</li>
<li>Insult to the modesty of women</li>
<li>Assault on women with intent to outrage her modesty</li>
<li>Indecent representation of women</li>
</ul>
<p>The total number of cases registered under this category in 2021 is 1,73,015, which translates to <code>12</code> cases in one year for every 1 Lac (1,00,000) population (25,000 households). The USA and Norway have similar numbers of around <code>11</code> cases per year for every 1 Lac population. It is obvious from the crime descriptions that these cases are copious enough to be registered, and they do not come up with any stigma attached, so the cases registered are on par with those of developed economies.</p>
</section>
<section id="pocso" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="pocso">POCSO</h3>
<p>POCSO is referred to as <code>Protection of children from sexual offences</code>. Often, these include acts of sexual assault, harassment, child pornography and others. So, to make this more holistic category, I have added selling and buying minor girls under this heading:</p>
<ul>
<li>Selling of minor girls</li>
<li>Buying of minor girls</li>
<li>POCSO Act</li>
</ul>
<p>The total number of cases registered under this crime heading is 52,850 in 2021, which translates to approximately <code>4</code> cases per year for every 1 Lac. If we include child abuse cases, the majority would be of child marriage and forced labour. The numbers would shoot up to <code>129</code> cases per year for every 1 Lac. Of course, it is a bothersome problem in India, with millions of children being subjected to physical, emotional, and sexual abuse every year. The USA has similar numbers of around <code>130</code> cases per year for every 1 Lac.</p>
<p>Although the cases registered are on par with developed economies, are they still underreported?</p>
</section>
<section id="sexual-violence" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sexual-violence">Sexual Violence</h3>
<p>Sexual Violence is any harmful or unwanted sexual behaviour that is imposed on women. It includes abusive sexual contact, forced engagement in sexual acts, attempted or completed sexual acts with a woman without her consent, unwanted touching, incest, and others. In India, we can register cases of Sexual Violence under the following five headings as per my comprehension.</p>
<ul>
<li>Human Trafficking</li>
<li>Rape</li>
<li>Attempt to commit rape</li>
<li>Immoral traffic prevention act</li>
<li>Murder with rape or gang rape</li>
</ul>
<p>The total cases registered under this crime heading is 37,462 in 2021, which translates to approximately <code>3</code> cases per year for every 1 Lac While in the USA, it is approximately <code>20</code> cases per year for every 1 Lac. Based on these statistics, are developed countries more dangerous for women to stay and live in compared to India?</p>
<p>As per the NFHS ( National Family Health Survey ) conducted in the year 2015-16, approximately <code>86%</code> of the Sexual Violence Crimes in India don’t get reported. This learning would equate to that of the USA, which has 21 cases per year for every 1 Lac of population. So, is there any social stigma attached to a rape victim?</p>
</section>
<section id="cyber-crime" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="cyber-crime">Cyber Crime</h3>
<p>Cybercrime affects women the most. It subjects them to mental and emotional harassment. The most common cyber crimes against women include blackmail, threats, cyberpornography, and publishing of obscene sexual content. It also includes stalking, bullying, defamation, morphing, and the establishment of fake profiles.</p>
<p>Although we see numerous fake profiles and online abuse of women, only 2,597 cases were registered in 2021. In the USA, the number of reported cases is approximately 10,000. This type of crime looks to be malignant. So, women block the online perpetrator’s profile or go offline from social media for a few days instead of reporting. Under this context, are women fostering any societal habit?</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Earlier, I planned to provide my opinion on the questions in the previous sections. However, questions are sufficient for the reader to introspect and comprehend. Of course, every reader can understand in many ways, but if we realize that everything starts at home, then I’m happy.</p>
<p>Finally, I would like to present the correlation plot among these categories. The notable fact in this correlation plot is that <code>Domestic Violence</code> is highly correlated with <code>Harassment</code> and <code>Sexual Violence</code>. Does it communicate how we treat women at home, and does the same behaviour percolate in society?</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/crimes-against-women/images/Plot4_ViolenceCategory_Correlation.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="846"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Finally I would like to end the essay with a famour quote from Swami Vivekananda - “All Nations have attained greatness by praying proper respect to women. That Country and nation which do not respect women has never become great, nor will ever be in future”.</p>
<p>Note: Readers can go through the detailed visualization in my <a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/TidyTuesday/tidy-analysis/22072024/">TidyTuesday</a> Blog.</p>
<script src="https://giscus.app/client.js" data-repo="ArunKoundinya/CanvassAndAnalyze" data-repo-id="R_kgDOLTnAQQ" data-category="General" data-category-id="DIC_kwDOLTnAQc4CdYId" data-mapping="pathname" data-strict="0" data-reactions-enabled="1" data-emit-metadata="0" data-input-position="bottom" data-theme="transparent_dark" data-lang="en" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>crimes against women</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/crimes-against-women/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/crimes-against-women/image.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cognitive Delusion under Information Deluge?</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/cognitive_delusion/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/cognitive_delusion/image.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="400"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><span style="font-size: small;">Note: this blog is not about mental disorders.</span></p>
<section id="delusion-vs-hallucation" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="delusion-vs-hallucation">Delusion vs Hallucation?</h2>
<p>Everyone would doubt the difference between delusion and Hallucination. I hope this section will bring the initial conceptual clarity.</p>
<p>Delusion, in simple words, is having firm beliefs despite contrary evidence. Hallucination is something living in that belief or world, although it doesn’t exist.</p>
<p>In the psychiatric world and for mental disorder patients, they often overlap.</p>
<p>But as of now, let us step in and see these two through two different lenses.</p>
<p><em>Example1</em>: Assume that <code>Subhash</code> loved playing cricket since his childhood. He has been to the best coaching centers in the city to get trained. But for practice, he used to play with his school friends instead of cricket ground friends. This made him believe that he was the best in his game. During <code>under 14</code> selections, he didn’t fare well compared to his peers as per the selection committee. However, <code>Subhash</code> labeled this selection as grossly politically favored to certain sections of kids as he could not believe that his skill wasn’t up to the mark. So, he still believes that he is best at his game, although there is clear evidence that he isn’t. In this scenario <code>Subhash</code> is in a delusion that he has all the necessary skills to be part of the district team.</p>
<p><em>Example2</em>: Let’s exaggerate the behaviour of <code>Subhash</code> for this example. <code>Subhash</code> has been continuously rejected for four consecutive years and got good feedback from coaches to improve his technique and skill. Despite this, he still believes that he is good at his game. Later, to overcome these several setbacks, he abandoned attending cricket coaching classes and instead formed a small team with his school friends and lived in that world. He was so invincible with his school friends that he derived a theory and started communicating that the selection committee and coaches were corrupted, and they stopped his growth intentionally and hid his talent to resurface to the world. At this stage, he is hallucinating unknown events, which can be termed a hallucination.</p>
<p>Reference:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/mental-health/hallucinations-vs-delusions">Link</a></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="what-is-delusion-in-information-era" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="what-is-delusion-in-information-era">What is delusion in information era?</h2>
<p>In the information era, we have deluge access to information, which I would like to categorize into four ways:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Info A</strong>: Information that we like and is relevant.</li>
<li><strong>Info B</strong>: Information that we don’t like and is relevant.</li>
<li><strong>Info C</strong>: Information that we like and isn’t relevant.</li>
<li><strong>Info D</strong>: Information that we don’t care.</li>
</ul>
<p>There is no empirical information about the distribution of this information. But as per my personal experience, I can say that the majority of the information sits in <code>Info D</code>. But we all care about <code>Info A</code> and <code>Info C</code>.</p>
<p>Since we delve into the information that we only care about, there is a 100% chance that we form many <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/basics/bias">biases</a>. These <code>biases</code> will create our self-full prophecy belief system and might push us into delusion.</p>
</section>
<section id="why-do-we-have-delusion-and-its-probable-reasons" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="why-do-we-have-delusion-and-its-probable-reasons">Why do we have delusion and its probable reasons?</h2>
<p>The primary outcome of a delusion is a conclusion without caring for any further evidence to confirm or solidify that evidence. Rather than going through the variety of information in this era, we might get into the deluge of the information we believe. Also, Google answers what we ask and doesn’t offer what we need for our holistic thought process.</p>
<p>There are multiple reasons to have our delusions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Genetic factors</li>
<li>Biological factors</li>
<li>Psychological factors</li>
<li>Environmental factors</li>
</ul>
<p>In pre-Google era, information deluge isn’t available. Now, in the information era, this particular environment would contribute to the creation of delusions.</p>
<p>Reference:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/9599-delusional-disorder">Link</a></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="closing-remarks" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="closing-remarks">Closing remarks</h2>
<p>There aren’t any suggestions from my side, as this is still a learning process. Furthermore, I have genuinely believed in technology and its progress. So, the onus lies on the user to use it rather than to become dependent on the devices. Also, it is wise to turn to humans occasionally instead of a device, as humans design devices.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: xsmall;">Note: I have used Grammarly to correct English for this blog. ChatGPT isn’t used at all for this blog.</span></p>
<script src="https://giscus.app/client.js" data-repo="ArunKoundinya/CanvassAndAnalyze" data-repo-id="R_kgDOLTnAQQ" data-category="General" data-category-id="DIC_kwDOLTnAQc4CdYId" data-mapping="pathname" data-strict="0" data-reactions-enabled="1" data-emit-metadata="0" data-input-position="bottom" data-theme="transparent_dark" data-lang="en" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>



</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>pyschology</category>
  <category>reflection</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/cognitive_delusion/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Extended Learnings -124 | Indian Culture | Perennial Cycle of Ānanda ( Bliss )</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning124/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>This blog piece comes almost after a year but at the right time, albeit there is a long hiatus. Lately, I have started a Spiritual YouTube Channel (in line with this blog series), wherein I’m sharing personal-level comprehension instead of metaphysical levels.</p>
<p>Here is the link to my YouTube Channel { <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W6DqGmzeoM8&amp;list=PL1pdvanb8-ka0_MlE_AQjP2aRm1vFSnjX">Link</a> } ; kindly subscribe if you enjoyed this series.</p>
<p>While I have completed the explanation of the Gnana, Karma &amp; Bhakti Yoga videos, I have realized that there is an underlying concept of perennial happiness by combining these three Yogas.</p>
<p>Before delving directly into the blog, let me summarize the prime pointers mentioned in the Video Series.</p>
<p>Re-cap of YouTube Channel First 4 Videos:</p>
<p>The root cause of unhappiness is our own thinking or thought process. Since our thought process hinders us from seeing the “world as-is” and instead, we see “the world as we want to see.”</p>
<p>Gnana Yoga: If we need to see the “world as-is,” the prime thing is not to get involved but to just observe. Such that our thought process changes from reacting to comprehending the situation.</p>
<p>Karma Yoga: After we comprehend the situation, we need to act based on the revised thought process which, in turn, is based on our comprehension.</p>
<p>Bhakti Yoga: Once we start to act on the thoughts based on comprehension rather than reaction, we tend to observe that the results of the actions we take are going in a positive direction. This, in turn, helps us to love our own thought process.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning124/version_arun_image.jpeg" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="693"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><u><strong>Blog</strong></u>:</p>
<p>Let us consider an acting profession.</p>
<p>Acting: Assume that one wants to become a good and better actor. Let us assume that he/she thinks about his/her career impartially, leading to the selection of roles with clarity in their thought process. Once he/she selects the roles, he/she gives his/her 100% in acting. However, the results are in the hands of critics and audiences, which can go either way.</p>
<p>Since he/she is clear in his/her thought process to become a better actor, he/she takes cues from past roles and learns from critics and audiences, and further implementing them in their next movie. His/Her learnings and comprehensions about being an actor improve movie after movie. He/She tries to become a better version of thyself compared to their previous movie, as their impartial thought process focuses on being a good and better actor. This makes them happier, knowing that he/she is progressing to become a better actor. Since, there is no limit for betterment; His/Her experimentation and exploration to become a better continuous till he/she strives for it. At a distance it looks like a diligent and hardworking model. However, upon closer inspection, one can discern a continuous journey of self improvement. The Ultimate happiness is about progressing thyself without future regrets. If one can take actions “now” resulting from clear thought process, that action is the first step towards happiness. Moreover, when one’s purpose is beyond their existence, their continuous action is bounded by love towards upon their “clear” thought process. This iterative process of taking incremental steps in our own life leads to various degrees of “delta happiness”, ultimately guiding us into a perpetual state of bliss.</p>
<p>I will be creating a YouTube Video as well on the similar lines in next couple of days. ______________________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>My previous blogs for reference -</p>
<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/learnings-indian-culture/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/learnings-indian-culture/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning101/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning101/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning102/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning102/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning103/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning103/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning104/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning104/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning105/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning105/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning106/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning106/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning107/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning107/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning108/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning108/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning109/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning109/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning111/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning111/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning112/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning112/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning113/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning113/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning114/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning114/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning115/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning115/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning116/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning116/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning117/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning117/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning118/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning118/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning119/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning119/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning120/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning120/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning121/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning121/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning122/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning122/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning123/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning123/</a></p></li>
</ul>
<script src="https://giscus.app/client.js" data-repo="ArunKoundinya/CanvassAndAnalyze" data-repo-id="R_kgDOLTnAQQ" data-category="General" data-category-id="DIC_kwDOLTnAQc4CdYId" data-mapping="pathname" data-strict="0" data-reactions-enabled="1" data-emit-metadata="0" data-input-position="bottom" data-theme="transparent_dark" data-lang="en" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>




 ]]></description>
  <category>spirituality</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning124/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LOVE &amp; TRUST - Season -1 | Episode - 2</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode2/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>Continued from previous blog -&nbsp;<a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode2" class="uri">Link</a></p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode2/image.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="332"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><u><em>A few years ago,</em></u></p>
<p>A young girl in her early twenties, draped in an exquisite blue coloured silk saree, nervously waiting for her loved one outside an Engineering college.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Her dilated eyes turned misty when she saw a resembled face from a distance, and then she started flying towards him and hugged him tightly and said, “I love you, Sanjay”. { Yes, this is the same Sanjay of the first Episode }</p>
<p>“Pooja, there are so many students and lecturers around”.</p>
<p>She heard nothing but clutched him more tightly as if he would slip away from her.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Sanjay responded by kissing her forehead and said, “Love you too, Pooja”,</p>
<p>After feeling his kiss, Pooja came to her senses and said, “I’m sorry, Sanjay. I couldn’t stop myself as we are meeting after a couple of years”.</p>
<p>He took her to the nearest Ganapathi mandir, which is a few miles away from his University and vowed that he would never leave her hand under any circumstances.</p>
<p>“I’m incredibly sorry that I had to ditch you because of our minor misunderstandings at that time. I never imagined you would come over again for me.”</p>
<p>“Thanks to social media, I have been following you under a ghost account for the last year. So, it was effortless to find you and your Univ. But, you never felt to look for me, Sanjay, after we broke up?”</p>
<p>“I did. But I felt guilty about what I did for you? I’m sorry,” Sanjay said as tears rolled out his eyes.</p>
<p>Pooja kissed his cheek and said, ” I love you. Let us be together again forever.”</p>
<p>“It is tough to find a loved one. It’s tougher to find a loved one who knocked on your door. How can I leave you?”</p>
<p>They hugged inside the temple as if air couldn’t pass through them. They spent their time till dawn and had a sumptuous dinner in a nearby eatery, and later Sanjay dropped her at her University, which was just two hundred miles away.</p>
<p>It took a year to find out for Pooja that Sanjay was running a parallel story along with Swati, Sanjay’s classmate.</p>
<p>She came to know this when she decided to surprise Sanjay for Valentine’s day; however, to her surprise, she saw them going into a theatre cuddling each other. At that moment, she wants to quarrel with him then. But, out of her unparalleled love towards him, she left the place in tears.</p>
<p>Pooja felt that if she showed her true love to him, he would return with unconditional love. So she waited a couple of months to see whether Sanjay would confess to his behaviour. But, it never took to that course of action.</p>
<p>Pooja doesn’t want to turn this into a bitter relationship and a nasty breakup. But chose to avoid him consistently in the name of her career and aspirations. In the beginning, it turned him off; nonetheless,&nbsp;&nbsp;having a backup, he picks to settle with Swati rather than search for true love.</p>
<p>On the other side, Pooja sobbed for months to overcome this trouble backstabbed relationship.</p>
<p><em>Back to Present in Psychotherapy Clinic</em></p>
<p>” Please wait outside or speak to my receptionist for the next queue. I’m already engaged with a client”, said Swati’s mother, the therapist.</p>
<p>Receptionist said, “Sir, there is a waiting for 30 mins. I request you to please wait in the lobby”.</p>
<p>“Sure”</p>
<p>He walked towards the lobby and saw a beautiful woman draped in a blue saree. She looked engrossed in reading a cine magazine, and it took a while for his dull mind to recognise that she was none other than Pooja.&nbsp;</p>
<p>He felt on cloud nine to see her at the right time and thanked God for this moment.&nbsp;</p>
<p>” Pooja, How are you?”</p>
<p>Pooja casually looked at Sanjay, then got excited to see him again after a couple of years and said, ” I’m amazing. How are you?”</p>
<p>” I’m fantastic too.”</p>
<p>” How come you are here, Sanjay ?”</p>
<p>” I came here for a counselling session; I’m going through a tough phase in my life. And how come you are here, Pooja? Are you here for counselling too?”</p>
<p>” No”</p>
<p>” Let me guess. Are you working here?”</p>
<p>She smiled and said, “No.&nbsp;But I’m surprised that you contemplated a counselling session. These days men are evolving as vulnerable and untrained to manage themselves.”</p>
<p>“Times change, Pooja, and men have a heart too! And I couldn’t stop flattering you; you look ravishing and stunning.”</p>
<p>Pooja beamed and said, “Thank you!!!!”</p>
<p>” It is fine. But, first, tell me why you are here?”</p>
<p>Pooja smiled and said,” I’m here for my Husband. He is presently having a counselling session with the therapist.”</p>
<p><em>&lt;&lt;&lt; To be Continued &gt;&gt;&gt;</em></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>love</category>
  <category>story</category>
  <category>trust</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode2/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LOVE &amp; TRUST - Season -1 | Episode - 1</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode1/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode1/image.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="577"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>It is about 5:45 P.M.</p>
<p>Sanjay is shifting the gears in traffic and manoeuvring his car (like a snake) in haste. He could hardly see the traffic through his misty eyes and, in an unmindful state, pulled out the mobile from his left pocket and dialled his friend Raj.</p>
<p>“Raj, can you come ASAP to our regular hangout place?”</p>
<p>Being his thickest friend from the last year, he understood the situation, felt his necessity, and said, “Sure, Sanjay. I will reach in a couple of minutes. Will be waiting for you.”</p>
<p>Car brushed the median strip and gained a dent in the rear door. However, Sanjay’s current emotions made him pay little attention to this improvement, and without stopping anywhere else, he reached the hangout place in ten minutes.</p>
<p>“Raj, can you help to order a cup of fresh ginger tea for me, please”</p>
<p>Raj went to the stall, which is adjacent to the bakery, And in ten minutes, he came with two cups of tea and placed them on the lawn seat.</p>
<p>“Sanjay, what happened? Why do you look so dull? Is it about Swathi?”</p>
<p>Sanjay behaved as if he lived too emotionally mature and could handle things efficiently.</p>
<p>“Yes”, said he and then sipped the hot tea and continued, ” she ditched me. she said she is seeing another *ss**le”.</p>
<p>“How can she do it to me, Raj? I have been with her for two years and have always given her enough space for her privacy. So is that the mistake I made?”</p>
<p>In anguish, he sipped the entire hot tea in a couple of gulps and continued, “Nevertheless, I can handle this. I will consider this moment as a blip in my personal life.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Raj’s phone vibrated, and slowly he picked up the phone from his right pocket and texted - “<em>He is with me will call you later</em>.”</p>
<p>“Raj, are u seeing a girl too?”</p>
<p>Raj responded with a shy smile and said, “Yes.”</p>
<p>“Be aware, Raj. Take me as an example. Never trust these girls blindly. For example, see how cruel Swathi is… First, she kissed me, and now she is ready to kiss another one…”</p>
<p>“Sanjay, be kind to her. She is your girlfriend”.</p>
<p>“You are right, Raj. But it isn’t any more”is”. It is her choice—preferences changes as time matures. We have to respect the same. So let it go, man.”</p>
<p>They chatted about office politics for the next half an hour and departed.</p>
<p>Sanjay reached the home safely and texted the same to Raj. Then, after having a good dinner with his parents, he went to his room and locked the room tightly and cried like a baby and slept off.</p>
<p>For the next month, he posted many motivational messages on social media and got numerous likes, ultimately leading to a boost in his self-esteem.</p>
<p>One fine working day, he took off from work and went to the theatre to watch a movie to ease his work pressures. Just before the interval, he spotted Raj and Swathi in upper corner seats, having their love time.</p>
<p>During the interval, Sanjay encountered them at the snack area, smiled, and responded, “Hey guys, hope you are having a lovely time together. Your pair is heavenly.”</p>
<p>Swathi understood his internal sarcasm and said, “I hope you are fine with our relationship.”</p>
<p>“Yea.Yea. Yeah… I am much stronger now. I have a huge career in front of me, which is more important than anything else.”</p>
<p>Sanjay acted as if he got a text message and said,&nbsp;“Guys, you have to carry on. I have to leave for work now. I just got an emergency text.” and immediately left the place with hidden frustration.</p>
<p>Again in the night, after his dinner, he went to his room and cried like a baby and slept off.</p>
<p>After thinking for a long time, he jotted down three questions, which he felt he get answers to immediately in order to reduce his worries and improve his self-esteem.</p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;1) Why is this always happening to me?</p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;2) Whom should I trust?&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;3) How much can I trust someone?</p>
<p>He turned to his miniature electronic device to get the answers, which re-directed him to consult a psychotherapist.</p>
<p>With the aid of the Practo App, he booked a top-rated psychotherapist who, in turn, practices far away from his home.</p>
<p>Without procrastination, he quickly drove to the place post the appointment confirmation.</p>
<p>After entering the consultant’s room, he realised that the therapist was none other than Swathi’s mother.</p>
<p>His brain triggered his famous question, “How Much I Can Trust Her?….”</p>
<p><em>&lt;&lt;&lt; To be Continued &gt;&gt;&gt;</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>love</category>
  <category>story</category>
  <category>trust</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/Love_n_Trust_Season1_Episode1/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Glossary - 103 | Indian Culture | Sanātana Dharma</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary103/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>&nbsp;Continuing from the previous blog</p>
<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary101/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary101/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary102/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary102/</a></p></li>
</ul>
<p>_________________________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>Before we move our identity from&nbsp;<strong>ATMAN</strong>&nbsp;to&nbsp;<strong>BRAHMAN</strong>, it is necessary to establish identity with&nbsp;<strong>ATMAN.</strong> As leading thyself comes before leading others.</p>
<p><em>We left the previous blog with this question:</em></p>
<p>But how can we move our identity to BRAHMAN? Are there any Universal rules or guiding principles?</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary103/image.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="731"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Yes, there are Universal rules called “eternal laws” termed as&nbsp;<strong>Sanātana Dharma</strong>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>If we observe, the “Sun” is one the most prominent source of our life. How can Sun provide so much energy for generations after generations?&nbsp;</p>
<p>On a spiritual dimension, Sun is a perfect live example of “eternal laws” in action. (&nbsp;Link&nbsp;to an earlier series blog - Our Relatable Personal God )</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Sun generates the energy within</p></li>
<li><p>It gives power but doesn’t take it back.</p></li>
<li><p>It shows up every day with the same intensity.</p></li>
<li><p>It plays a prominent role in all the seasons to occur.</p></li>
<li><p>It holds together the planets of the solar system with its gravitational pull.</p></li>
<li><p>It doesn’t tell how to radiate. But powers light to reflect thyself.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>All the above sentences summarize - being in “<strong><em>Service</em></strong>” and “<strong><em>Awareness</em></strong>”. This is all about&nbsp;<strong>Sanātana Dharma.</strong></p>
<p>Alternatively, if we try to link Suns’ way of life to us, it translates as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Constant Self Inquiry leads us to a state of “Consciousness,” i.e., being with our showman. Wherein we get enlightened about ourselves.</p></li>
<li><p>Once we are enlightened, it is about giving back knowledge to the seekers through self-inquiry.</p></li>
<li><p>Results don’t matter when being in “Service”. It is about being dutiful to one’s prescribed duty.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;Above three looks familiar in our journey of the previous series of blogs. { Summarised in this version of the blog -&nbsp;Link&nbsp;}</p>
<p><strong>Sanātana Dharma</strong> is about the way of living and is not related to any religion, which is the crux of Indian culture.</p>
<p>_________________________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;">P.S.: Scientifically, Sun radiates its energy by nuclear fusion. It means it has to lose itself, i.e., mass, to release energy. The most exciting fact is that by the time the Sun becomes a white dwarf, it would only reduce 1% of the Sun’s mass. Thus, just 1% of the Sun’s mass generates energy for 4 billion years.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;">Think about being in “Self-Inquiry” for our lifetim!!!!</span></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>spirituality</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary103/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Glossary - 102 | Indian Culture | Aham Brahmasmi</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary102/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>&nbsp;Continuing from the previous blog -&nbsp;<a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary101/" class="uri">Link</a></p>
<p>_________________________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary102/image.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="357"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>In the previous blog, we learned about ATMAN. It is nothing but a consciousness that keeps us moving ahead. If we identify ourselves with ATMAN, ATMAN defines us.</p>
<p>If we zoom out from the unit level to the environment, there would be several ATMANs ( or consciousness ). It is like several consciousnesses trying to guide their living entity. To draw an analogy, it is like people wearing a head torch and living together. ( Head torch can be your ATMAN )</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary102/enlightment.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="610"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>For generations, there have been many species and lives that “the head torch has guided.” Also, surrounding us, the lives, planets, and galaxies evolved so synchronously as if there is a continuous power supply to those “head torches.” That Continuous supply of power that has powered the lives and larger universe is called&nbsp;<u><strong>BRAHMAN</strong></u>. In other words, it is also called super consciousness. ( This doesn’t mean to propagate that there is a superintelligence synchronizing the lives, but to give a context of what Brahman is. ).&nbsp;</p>
<p>In an alternative way - Even though there have been considerable changes like we are launching so many satellites, increasing the global temperature, etc.; The sun appears every day, all planets revolve around the sun, and all seasons come to us every year ( for which we depend). So irrespective of the Universal Maya, the universe constantly evolves and empowers many lives in its journey.</p>
<p>Suppose&nbsp;<strong>ATMAN</strong>&nbsp;is like recognizing the guiding light within us, which empowers us.&nbsp;<strong>BRAHMAN</strong>&nbsp;is like a guiding light for so many lives that empowers others.</p>
<p>If we move our identity from&nbsp;<strong>ATMAN</strong>&nbsp;to&nbsp;<strong>BRAHMAN</strong>, we term it “<u><strong><em>Aham Brahmasmi</em></strong></u>.”&nbsp;</p>
<p>But how can we move our identity to BRAHMAN? Are there any Universal rules or guiding principles?</p>
<p>- Answer in the next blog</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>spirituality</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary102/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Glossary - 101 | Indian Culture | Atman &amp; Maya</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary101/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>Before moving to the next series, I felt like sharing some glossaries with the audience, which makes the understanding more complete and starters can connect the dots.</p>
<p>I have planned for three blog posts that will get published over the next month or so. Maybe I will add more in the future.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary101/image.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Let us recollect the first blog of the previous series (&nbsp;<a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/learnings-indian-culture/">Link</a>). ( Rewriting a part of it which is required for this blog )</p>
<p>How do we view a movie on the Screen; Light has to fall on the movie reel which is been rotated by the wheel/motor system and in-turn that reel image is being imposed on the lens which gets enlarged and seen on the silver screen.</p>
<p>This is exactly how we see the world;&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Light is our Intelligence</p></li>
<li><p>Reel is our Thought Process or Information Available</p></li>
<li><p>Wheel is the brain that process the information or thought process</p></li>
<li><p>Lens are our senses and can be equated to Eyes</p></li>
<li><p>Screen is the world that we see</p></li>
</ul>
<p>But who is running the show?&nbsp;</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary101/learning-2.jpeg" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="594"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>In the above explanation, we see the world from our thought process or, to simply put - “We see what we want to see.” We term this as “<u><strong>MAYA</strong></u>.” It is the same “Maya” we often hear from our elders or texts, which translates to “nothing is real, but it is merely objects of our projections/perceptions.”</p>
<p>Now let us assume that there is no reel, meaning there is no thought process or information available. Then, we just ‘SEE’ it. But who helps us to see? Is it not all by ourselves? If we observe newborn kids, whenever they see something new, they stare at it for some time and respond as per the environment. As we grow, our thought process comes into play, so we PROCESS &amp; SEE. When we SEE rather than PROCESS &amp; SEE, we remove our prejudiced beliefs and start learning, accepting, and seeing new information, thus gaining more clarity of the context. As we reduce our pre-processing unit, the internal energy/force can be diverted for our benefit; therefore, enjoying a less stressful life and attaining more clarity leads to a peaceful life.</p>
<p>To remove that PROCESS from our equation requires a conscious effort. At times this happens by luck or due to survival necessity. Linking back to the movie theatre example, what do we see on the screen if there is no reel? We will see the light coming from the projector, and now the showman is running the show, but no movie is playing. Then who is the showman? Showman is that guiding force within us that wants to enlighten us. So, to meet the showman, we need to make that conscious effort to remove the MAYA. The showman or this consciousness to be aware of MAYA clutches is termed “<u><strong>ATMAN</strong></u>.” Atman means nothing but our true “<u><strong><em>Self</em></strong></u>” which wants to guide us. If we stay with Atman forever, we will be liberated and peaceful.</p>
<p>Then what is BRAHMAN?</p>
<p>– Will explain in next blog</p>
<p>________________________________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>I hope I have tried to explain the concept in a better way and in easy way. Please leave your feedback.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>spirituality</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureGlossary101/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Extended Learnings - Summary | What Next?</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/ExtendedLearnings-WhatNext/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<section id="summary-of-24-blog-post-in-one-go" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-24-blog-post-in-one-go"><u><em>Summary of 24 Blog Post in one go</em></u>:&nbsp;</h4>
<p>In this series of posts, we have observed Rishi, who gets enlightened through self-inquiry with a genuine inherent desire to meet the Showman; they would like to come forward to share a similar experience to his few selected disciples; thus, ‘the Rishi’ becomes ‘the Guru.’ These Rishis’ have created a way for us (via Personal God) to get liberated and realize the Showman within ourselves.</p>
<p>We learned that ‘Brahmacharya’ are the people who embark on their travel to meet the Showman. So, to get motivated to stay on the journey to pursue Showman, they started to pray to the Sun, who is more visible and tangible; and then continue their path for the ultimate Showman.</p>
<p>Rishis Disciple is now in a confusion mode ( a learning soul will always be in that way). He learned about the inner light dualities among the people and envisaged that his realization of Showman must be a Sacrifice which is nothing to sacrifice that he will realize him. His question of “why pooja” made him realize that it should not be a ritual but a method to concentrate on discovering God. Also, whatever work we do, if we perform as per the direction of Showman, we will attain peace by not thinking about the reward and living out of the vicious loop of Gunas.</p>
<p>Now Shishya is trying to learn about the pains and their conflicts. He realized that conflict is his image of the past that differs from the present. Also, the conflict will be no more only when one tries to understand the conflict. So finally, he realizes that he must come above his conflict and understand the truth.</p>
<p>He started to live with the truth that God is within us and everywhere</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/ExtendedLearnings-WhatNext/om.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img"></p>
</figure>
</div>
</section>
<section id="what-next" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="what-next"><u><em>What Next?</em></u></h4>
<ul>
<li>One of my close friends mentioned that the content is good; why don’t you post it as a book after completing your blog series. However, publishing a book requires much more rewriting and adding more details. In this base version of the book, I copy pasted the blogs for binge reading. We will revise this document together in a couple of years and make it better. (&nbsp;<a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1IizWHZjMU_vdo-wRVyBQ_oe2puL7SKse/view?pli=1">Link for the PDF</a>&nbsp;)</li>
</ul>
<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>Few of you resonate that this is good to read. But, most of us cannot relate to the current status quo. So soon, in a couple of months will start writing blogs on “ Contemporary Learnings of Indian Cultures,” which will help us in the current times. I hope you may like that too.</li>
</ul>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>spirituality</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/ExtendedLearnings-WhatNext/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Extended Learnings -123 | Indian Culture | Living in Truth !</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning123/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning123/image.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="400"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><u><em>Continuing from previous blogs</em></u>:</p>
<p>We have observed where the Rishi who gets enlightened through self inquiry with a true inherent desire to meet the Showman; they would like to come forward to share the similar experience to his few selected disciples; and thus ‘the Rishi’ becomes ‘the Guru’.&nbsp; Who have created a way for each and everyone of us (In terms of Personal God) to get us liberated and realize the Showman within ourselves. And then we learnt that people who embark a travel to meet the showman are termed as ‘Brahmacharya’; To get motivated to meet the showman they start to pray the Sun who is more visible and tangible; and then continue their path for the ultimate showman.</p>
<p>Rishis Disciple is now in a confusion mode asking about the inner light dualities among the people and again got into confusion when he envisaged that his realization to showman has to be Sacrificed to realize him. His question of “<em>why pooja</em>” made him to realize that it should not be a ritual but a method to concentrate to realize the god. Whatever work we do, if we perform as per direction of showman we will attain peace and not thinking about the reward and living out of vicious loop of Gunas.</p>
<p>Now Shishya is trying to learn about the pains and its conflicts. And has learnt that the conflict is his past image with respect to the present. Also, the conflict will be no more only when one tries to understand the conflict. Finally, leading him to realize that it is his duty to come above his own conflict and understand the truth. Further, trying to learn the process of being with the truth for-ever.</p>
<p>We left the previous blog with this question.</p>
<p>After a while, for a change, Guruji asks, ” Since you understood the process of attaining Truth. Can you describe the process ?”</p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><u><strong><em>And then Rishi/Guru &amp; Shishya Dicusses in this way</em></strong></u>:</span></p>
<p>” &nbsp;Guruji, you have mentioned that the methods have to be different to attain truth. So one has to discover their methods.”</p>
<p>” Aren’t methods and process is same? ”</p>
<p>” How can it be Guruji? You have mentioned earlier that (<a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/">link</a>) methods are tools to realize showman. But they became mere rituals “, answered Shishya with a calmer voice.</p>
<p>” Methods got turned into rituals such that the process stays longer, but the process has lost its soul in due course”</p>
<p>Shishya looks deeper into his thought process by closing his eyes and nods his head.</p>
<p>” &nbsp;Guruji, these methods, of course, are created to realize the showman with-in, i.e., Atman. ”</p>
<p>Guruji nodded his head happily and said, ” Elaborate.”</p>
<p>” When you pray to a personal god, it means you are trying to speak to your showman. So also, when we do ‘<em>Abhishekam</em>’ with milk or water, we try to cleanse the soul and get closer to our showman. So to infer, every method is devised as a relentless effort to realize the showman with-in.”</p>
<p>Guruji felt satisfied by his responses and said, ” Then what is the process? ”</p>
<p>” Guruji, there is no process. We created the rules, but the actual process is to be with the showman in any activity we perform. ”</p>
<p>Guruji hinted to Shishya, ” In any activity that we perform? Right now, we are talking. Can this be as well ? ”</p>
<p>Shishya smiled and responded, ” Speaking to others and not to be confused with responding to others is an activity. In which we speak to a reflection of our showman with others. And whatever they speak is the real Naivedyam (&nbsp;<a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning109/">link</a>&nbsp;) to our showman itself.”</p>
<p>And Shishya continued with an enlightenment aura, ” Actually, all living beings and this entire universe are the reflections of our supreme showman. We are just a tiny part of the supreme showman. Understanding this Oneness of showman among all of us is the actual process of staying with showman forever.”</p>
<p>Guruji opened his eyes happily and said, ” Shabhash Shishya, now you are a truly enlightened person. You don’t need any other Guru. You are Guru by yourself”. Saying this, Guruji packed his bag and left the ashram on a happy note.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; — End of Guru Shishya Story —</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>My previous blogs for reference -</p>
<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/learnings-indian-culture/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/learnings-indian-culture/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning101/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning101/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning102/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning102/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning103/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning103/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning104/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning104/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning105/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning105/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning106/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning106/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning107/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning107/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning108/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning108/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning109/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning109/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning111/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning111/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning112/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning112/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning113/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning113/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning114/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning114/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning115/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning115/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning116/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning116/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning117/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning117/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning118/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning118/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning119/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning119/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning120/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning120/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning121/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning121/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning122/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning122/</a></p></li>
</ul>



 ]]></description>
  <category>spirituality</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning123/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Extended Learnings -121 | Indian Culture | Understanding Truth !</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning122/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning122/image.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><u><em>Continuing from previous blogs</em></u>:</p>
<p>We have observed where the Rishi who gets enlightened through self inquiry with a true inherent desire to meet the Showman; they would like to come forward to share the similar experience to his few selected disciples; and thus ‘the Rishi’ becomes ‘the Guru’.&nbsp; Who have created a way for each and everyone of us (In terms of Personal God) to get us liberated and realize the Showman within ourselves. And then we learnt that people who embark a travel to meet the showman are termed as ‘Brahmacharya’; To get motivated to meet the showman they start to pray the Sun who is more visible and tangible; and then continue their path for the ultimate showman.</p>
<p>Rishis Disciple is now in a confusion mode asking about the inner light dualities among the people and again got into confusion when he envisaged that his realization to showman has to be Sacrificed to realize him. His question of “<em>why pooja</em>” made him to realize that it should not be a ritual but a method to concentrate to realize the god. Whatever work we do, if we perform as per direction of showman we will attain peace and not thinking about the reward and living out of vicious loop of Gunas.</p>
<p>Now Shishya is trying to learn about the pains and its conflicts. And has learnt that the conflict is his past image with respect to the present. Also, the conflict will be no more only when one tries to understand the conflict. Finally, leading him to realize that it is his duty to come above his own conflict and understand the truth.</p>
<p>We left the previous blog with this question.</p>
<p>” I understand that Guruji, but what work should I do by staying with the truth for life long other than staying in bliss. Of course, which is our ultimate goal. I mean after reaching the goal what should I do for the rest of my life. ”</p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><u><strong><em>And then Rishi/Guru responds in this way</em></strong></u>:</span></p>
<p>” What do you want to do in your life ? ” asks Guruji.</p>
<p>Shishya closes his eyes for a few seconds and responds, ” I want to stay with Showman forever. ”</p>
<p>” If you want to stay with Showman forever, what do you have to do? ”</p>
<p>” Guruji, I have a look inward and follow my inner light. ”</p>
<p>” You are in the right direction, Shishya. So it is simple, isn’t it so? When you find your Showman, why don’t you ask him what work you have to do for the rest of your life.”</p>
<p>Shishya looks confused, and he feels he is misguided and responds sharply,</p>
<p>” What is your use of being a Guru Guruji. If you are unable to guide me.”</p>
<p>Guruji looks at Shishya and nods with a smile.</p>
<p>Guruji asks again, ” Let me reframe it for you. Showman is the highest Guru, whom you will only meet through your inward journey. So, when you meet your highest Guru, why don’t you ask him directly. Why me? ”</p>
<p>Shishya, who still looks confused, didn’t say a word.</p>
<p>Guruji continues, ” Say, for example, if your goal is to win an Olympic medal in the running. And I helped my part by coaching you. It is a fact that it is only your sheer effort that will win you many medals. However, after a certain age, you might not be able to compete in the Olympics because of several regulatory restrictions. So what would you do?”</p>
<p>“Maybe I will become a coach. (or) I participate in other competitions (or) maybe pick another sport that doesn’t have any restrictions.”</p>
<p>” Perfect! ”</p>
<p>” So, you are not stopping. You are trying to stay with your ultimate bliss through other methods or activities,” responds Guruji</p>
<p>and continues, “The Truth remains the same. So, we must understand what we need to do to stay in that Truth forever. To not to lose our connection with the Showman.”</p>
<p>” So, you mean to say that I would discover what I would do for the rest of my life only when I reach the showman.? ” asks Shishya instantly.</p>
<p>” Most of us realize the Truth. But we won’t stay in that Truth for longer periods. We understand what it is but seldom comprehend it. ” responds Guruji with a calm and pleasant smile.</p>
<p>and continued, ” What do you have to do if you need to comprehend the ultimate truth.”</p>
<p>Shishya delves into his deep thinking and responds with his eyes closed, ” If I understood the process that made me realize the Truth. Then I will try to hinge on that process to stay in a more extended period or forever with the Truth. The process is like preparing for running, and the goal is like winning medals. ”</p>
<p>And Shishya continues in his heightened realization, ” When resolving our internal conflict, we understand only the temporary Truth. It isn’t possible to stay in that provisional Truth. But when we know the process of determining the conflict. We come above the conflict and remain with the Truth forever. Ultimately, this is the “process” that will stay with me for my journey for the rest of my life. Dhanyotsmi Guruji! ”</p>
<p>After a while, for a change, Guruji asks, ” Since you understood the process of attaining Truth. Can you describe the process ?”</p>
<p>— Answer in next blog</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>My previous blogs for reference -</p>
<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/learnings-indian-culture/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/learnings-indian-culture/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning101/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning101/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning102/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning102/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning103/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning103/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning104/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning104/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning105/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning105/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning106/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning106/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning107/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning107/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning108/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning108/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning109/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning109/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning111/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning111/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning112/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning112/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning113/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning113/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning114/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning114/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning115/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning115/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning116/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning116/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning117/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning117/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning118/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning118/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning119/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning119/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning120/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning120/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning121/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning121/</a></p></li>
</ul>



 ]]></description>
  <category>spirituality</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning122/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Extended Learnings -121 | Indian Culture | Understanding Truth !</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning121/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning121/understanding.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="400"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><u><em>Continuing from previous blogs</em></u>:</p>
<p>We have observed where the Rishi who gets enlightened through self inquiry with a true inherent desire to meet the Showman; they would like to come forward to share the similar experience to his few selected disciples; and thus ‘the Rishi’ becomes ‘the Guru’.&nbsp; Who have created a way for each and everyone of us (In terms of Personal God) to get us liberated and realize the Showman within ourselves. And then we learnt that people who embark a travel to meet the showman are termed as ‘Brahmacharya’; To get motivated to meet the showman they start to pray the Sun who is more visible and tangible; and then continue their path for the ultimate showman.</p>
<p>Rishis Disciple is now in a confusion mode asking about the inner light dualities among the people and again got into confusion when he envisaged that his realization to showman has to be Sacrificed to realize him. His question of “<em>why pooja</em>” made him to realize that it should not be a ritual but a method to concentrate to realize the god. Whatever work we do, if we perform as per direction of showman we will attain peace and not thinking about the reward and living out of vicious loop of Gunas.</p>
<p>Now Shishya is trying to learn about the pains and its conflicts. And has learnt that the conflict is his past image with respect to the present. Also, the conflict will be no more only when one tries to understand the conflict.</p>
<p>We left the previous blog with this question.</p>
<p>Shishya started to ponder to what Guruji said and in few minutes he asks, ” If I just live around these conflicts and try to understand them, when can I reach an ultimate bliss situation and realize the showman. I doubt is there a showman in reality ? ”</p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><u><strong><em>And then Rishi/Guru responds in this way</em></strong></u>:</span></p>
<p>” Who has created these conflicts? ” asks Guruji.</p>
<p>Shishya, instead of reacting instantly, thinks calmly for a few seconds and responds, ” As you said Guruji, conflicts are created in our mind to our past. So, conflict is our creation. ”</p>
<p>” If you want to enjoy the conflict! what do you have to do? ”</p>
<p>” Guruji, that is an absurd question. How can one enjoy the conflict? ”</p>
<p>” You are not thinking Shishya. Give it a thought you have the answer. ”</p>
<p>Shishya closes his eyes for a minute; and he opens his eyes as if he got enlightened and responds, ” As you have said Guruji, conflict can be reduced when we try to understand the conflict. However, to enjoy the conflict we have to come above the conflict and start loving the process of learning the conflict ”</p>
<p>Guruji looks so revealed with his answers and smiles happily with a nod.</p>
<p>Guruji asks again, ” What makes you ponder, that is there a showman in reality or not? ”</p>
<p>” If there is in reality, you would be describing him and not the path to realizing him. Also, if there is one showman there would not be different religions ”</p>
<p>” Showman or truth is the same ”</p>
<p>” I could not comprehend your context, Guruji ”</p>
<p>” Our goal for showman is to reach a state of ultimate bliss, which in itself is the highest truth ” responds Guruji while sipping water</p>
<p>and continues, ” Truth remains the same. However, the path to understanding the truth might differ. I teach you my paths and others teach theirs. ”</p>
<p>” But why does it take so many years for your disciples to realize the truth ? ” asks Shishya instantly</p>
<p>” If they follow my path, they will understand my truth but not theirs’ ” responds Guruji with a calm and pleasant smile.</p>
<p>Shishya closes his eyes and goes into deep thinking and asks, ” Dhanyotsmi Gurudeva, I understand the starting point of the truth. If I have realized the showman, I have to come above the paths that you mentioned and create my path for him ”</p>
<p>Guruji nods his head and says, ” A while ago, when I have said to rethink on conflict. Instead of giving up you thought and responded and which is better than my answer. Remember, the entire cosmic is your brain. You have to make it light to make the best use for your happiness ”</p>
<p>After a while, shishya asks, ” What do I have to do after I realize the truth ”</p>
<p>This time Guruji replies, ” You stay with the truth ” instantaneously.&nbsp;</p>
<p>” I understand that Guruji, but what work should I do by staying with the truth for life long other than staying in bliss. Of course, which is our ultimate goal. I mean after reaching the goal what should I do for the rest of my life. ”</p>
<p>— Answer in next blog</p>
<p><u><strong><em>Glossary</em></strong></u>:</p>
<p>Universe is in your brain</p>
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning121/brain_universe.png" class="img-fluid" width="553"></p>
<p><a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/wildly-fun-new-paper-compares-the-human-brain-to-the-structure-of-the-universe">Link for your consumption</a></p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>My previous blogs for reference -</p>
<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/learnings-indian-culture/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/learnings-indian-culture/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning101/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning101/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning102/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning102/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning103/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning103/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning104/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning104/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning105/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning105/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning106/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning106/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning107/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning107/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning108/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning108/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning109/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning109/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning111/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning111/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning112/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning112/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning113/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning113/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning114/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning114/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning115/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning115/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning116/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning116/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning117/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning117/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning118/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning118/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning119/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning119/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning120/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning120/</a></p></li>
</ul>



 ]]></description>
  <category>spirituality</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning121/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Extended Learnings -120 | Indian Culture | Conflict Hypocrisy ?</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning120/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning120/allisone.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="400"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><u><em>Continuing from previous blogs</em></u>:</p>
<p>We have observed where the Rishi who gets enlightened through self inquiry with a true inherent desire to meet the Showman; they would like to come forward to share the similar experience to his few selected disciples; and thus ‘the Rishi’ becomes ‘the Guru’.&nbsp; Who have created a way for each and everyone of us (In terms of Personal God) to get us liberated and realize the Showman within ourselves. And then we learnt that people who embark a travel to meet the showman are termed as ‘Brahmacharya’; To get motivated to meet the showman they start to pray the Sun who is more visible and tangible; and then continue their path for the ultimate showman.</p>
<p>Rishis Disciple is now in a confusion mode asking about the inner light dualities among the people and again got into confusion when he envisaged that his realization to showman has to be Sacrificed to realize him. His question of “<em>why pooja</em>” made him to realize that it should not be a ritual but a method to concentrate to realize the god. Whatever work we do, if we perform as per direction of showman we will attain peace and not thinking about the reward and living out of vicious loop of Gunas.</p>
<p>Now Shishya is trying to learn about the pains and its conflicts. And has learnt that the conflict is his past image with respect to the present.</p>
<p>We left the previous blog with this question.</p>
<p>Shishya looks as if his quench for knowledge is done. However, within a moment with his unrest expression, ” It looks good on paper, would that be possible or is it a practical solution? ”</p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><u><strong><em>And then Rishi/Guru responds in this way</em></strong></u>:</span></p>
<p>” What makes you putative about our discussion? ” asks Guruji.</p>
<p>” It is like filling up the pond with river water. However, the river is 50 km away from the pond; and we have to fill using our cupped hands !! Vision is good, but it looks highly impossible that I doubt to pour even a drop in our lifetime. ”</p>
<p>” Superb! Then what did you realize from our discussions? ” asks Guruji with his usual serene smile.</p>
<p>” I have just realized that; it is not practical to follow your suggestions! ” says Shishya with a lot of intensity</p>
<p>” Superb!&nbsp; Let me help you here. In our discussion so far, what is the fact, and what is the opinion? ”</p>
<p>Shishya closed his eyes and responded,&nbsp; ” Fact is the realization that&nbsp;we get influenced/biased from our past. The opinion is one that where you have referred that we need to start from a fresh slate of mind in every moment of our life. ”</p>
<p>” So, you are deferring the opinion but not the fact. Am I right? ”</p>
<p>” Yes. That is the reason I have said it is not practical! “&nbsp;</p>
<p>” Good. If you agree that the fact is truth will that not help you? ”</p>
<p>” I need a solution !! ” responds Shishya with exacting intensity</p>
<p>Guruji smiles and responds, ” I will give you the solution that has worked for me. And you are saying that is not practical. So, I will be anachronistic as per your comprehension ”</p>
<p>” But I need a solution Guruji ! ” responds Shishya</p>
<p>” Let me tell you one more fact, in a hurry to look for a solution we do not internalize the fact. So, our realization will be in words but not inside our minds. So ideally, there might be several solutions available for our problems but none seems working for us. Consequentially, we either live with the fact or defer the fact. ”</p>
<p>” I can connect to this. But why does others’ solution doesn’t seem to be a right fit for us? ”</p>
<p>” Likewise there are several methods to realize god&nbsp;<em>{<a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/">refer earlier blog</a>}</em>&nbsp;there are several solutions to a problem. If we concentrate on methods we can never reach the end goal of ours but we might be reaching or working for someone else’s; which is of course not the solution we are looking for. “&nbsp; responds Guruji</p>
<p>” How can I find my solution? Your solution is very impractical and others’ solutions would be like a patch fix for that conflict. ”</p>
<p>” Wonderful Shishya!&nbsp; I would recommend that instead of finding the solution; try to learn more about your conflict and understand its roots.” answers Guruji to incite interest in Shishya.</p>
<p>Shishya started to ponder to what Guruji said and in few minutes he asks, ” If I just live around these conflicts and try to understand them, when can I reach an ultimate bliss situation and realize the showman. I doubt is there a showman in reality ? ”</p>
<p>— Answer in next blog</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>My previous blogs for reference -</p>
<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/learnings-indian-culture/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/learnings-indian-culture/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning101/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning101/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning102/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning102/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning103/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning103/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning104/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning104/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning105/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning105/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning106/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning106/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning107/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning107/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning108/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning108/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning109/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning109/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning111/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning111/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning112/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning112/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning113/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning113/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning114/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning114/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning115/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning115/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning116/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning116/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning117/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning117/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning118/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning118/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning119/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning119/</a></p></li>
</ul>



 ]]></description>
  <category>spirituality</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning120/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Extended Learnings -119 | Indian Culture | Conflict with Past!</title>
  <dc:creator>Arun Koundinya Parasa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning119/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning119/conflict.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="400"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><u><em>Continuing from previous blogs</em></u>:</p>
<p>We have observed where the Rishi who gets enlightened through self inquiry with a true inherent desire to meet the Showman; they would like to come forward to share the similar experience to his few selected disciples; and thus ‘the Rishi’ becomes ‘the Guru’.&nbsp; Who have created a way for each and everyone of us (In terms of Personal God) to get us liberated and realize the Showman within ourselves. And then we learnt that people who embark a travel to meet the showman are termed as ‘Brahmacharya’; To get motivated to meet the showman they start to pray the Sun who is more visible and tangible; and then continue their path for the ultimate showman.</p>
<p>Rishis Disciple is now in a confusion mode asking about the inner light dualities among the people and again got into confusion when he envisaged that his realization to showman has to be Sacrificed to realize him. His question of “<em>why pooja</em>” made him to realize that it should not be a ritual but a method to concentrate to realize the god. Whatever work we do, if we perform as per direction of showman we will attain peace and not thinking about the reward and living out of vicious loop of Gunas.</p>
<p>Now Shishya is trying to learn about the pains and its conflicts.</p>
<p>We left the previous blog with this question.</p>
<p>After few moments, ” How can we get out of the conflict zone!! Guruji. “,&nbsp; asks Shishya restlessly.</p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><u><strong><em>And then Rishi/Guru responds in this way</em></strong></u>:</span></p>
<p>Guruji smiles and responds, ” How do you define a zone? ”</p>
<p>” It means a territory; I’m assuming that you want me to re-define my question. Here it goes, how to get out of the conflict-territory that we habitually dwell?”</p>
<p>Guruji again responds with serene smile, ” Don’t dwell in that territory? “&nbsp;</p>
<p>” What would be the course. If we cannot come out of that territory? ”</p>
<p>Guruji quickly answers, ” This statement conflicts with your question itself. A while ago, you want to come out of that zone and now you are insisting that you cannot come out of that zone. Succinctly, you are pre-meditated to dwell in the conflict zone “&nbsp;</p>
<p>Shishya pauses for a minute and closes his eyes and pray, ” Guruji, let me rephrase my question. How to avoid being in that conflict zone ? ”</p>
<p>” Picking up from our earlier conversation (<a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning118/"><em>last blog</em></a>),&nbsp; conflict arises due to the interaction effect of past to present. Ideally, we have to start with a fresh slate of mind every moment in our life! ”</p>
<p>Shishya interrupted with anxiety and asked, ” Are you saying that we should have a consistent memory loss ”</p>
<p>Guruji says while he is signalling to sit on the bench,” That dead tree has become this bench with the aid of our memory. I don’t underestimate the power of our minds. What I mean is not to ax all the living trees because Guruji is enjoying his comfort on that bench. As we have formed an opinion based on what we observe from the original fact in the entire prejudice hierarchy ”</p>
<div class="quarto-video"><iframe data-external="1" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JgxY8S0Wbus?si=eTzKycBSqswZxYQx" width="600" height="400" title="" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>
<p><em>Watch from the 6th Minute onwards</em></p>
<p>Guruji continues, ” The conflict surfaces whenever we accept our opinions, our beliefs, and our so-called&nbsp; prejudices as mere facts. And this assumed fact will have a conflict with reality, as it is not the fact. To avoid that conflict we should have a fresh slate of mind, which means to stop forming opinions and just observe. ”</p>
<p>Shishya looks as if his quench for knowledge is done. However, within a moment with his unrest expression, ” It looks good on paper, would that be possible or is it a practical solution? ”</p>
<p>— Answer in next blog</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>My previous blogs for reference -</p>
<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/learnings-indian-culture/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/learnings-indian-culture/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning101/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning101/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning102/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning102/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning103/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning103/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning104/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning104/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning105/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning105/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning106/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning106/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning107/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning107/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning108/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning108/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning109/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning109/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning110/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning111/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning111/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning112/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning112/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning113/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning113/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning114/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning114/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning115/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning115/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning116/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning116/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning117/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning117/</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning118/" class="uri">https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning118/</a></p></li>
</ul>



 ]]></description>
  <category>spirituality</category>
  <guid>https://arunkoundinya.github.io/CanvassAndAnalyze/posts/IndianCultureLearning119/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
